<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Words on Pictures &#8211; Accidental Films and TV</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>Documentary Film and TV Productions</description>
	<lastBuildDate>
	Tue, 31 Oct 2017 15:56:54 +0000	</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.1.6</generator>
	<item>
		<title>A Short History of Documentary</title>
		<link>./../../../ashorthistoryofdocumentary/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../ashorthistoryofdocumentary/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 03:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Words on Pictures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Documentary film]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=213</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Erik Barnouw&#8217;s Documentary: A History of the Non-Fiction Film is a satisfying read. The book begins with French astronomer Pierre Jules Cesar Jansen&#8217;s experiments to ...]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Erik Barnouw&#8217;s <em>Documentary: A History of the Non-Fiction Film</em> is a satisfying read. The book begins with French astronomer Pierre Jules Cesar Jansen&#8217;s experiments to record the passage of Venus around the sun, the more well-known attempts of photographer Eadward Muybridge to examine the movement of race horses as precisely as possible, and the young Louis Lumiere&#8217;s invention of the <em>cinematographe</em> and its subsequent world domination as it showed themselves and the world to audiences around the globe. We meet Robert and Frances Flaherty, John Grierson, Dziga Vertov, Esfir Shub, Alberto Cavalcanti, Joris Ivens, Leni Riefenstahl, Humphrey Jennings and so many more &#8230;</p>
<p>The stories of social, technical and economic developments are integral to how these filmmakers came to and influenced documentary filmmaking. I was especially intrigued to learn how the changes over the years, influenced by the political climate around the world, affected the craft and how we have inherited that history in South Africa.</p>
<p>Working in television and video production for the past eleven years I am aware that documentary has a secondary status to that of fiction, or drama in South Africa. It is often said that documentary is the training ground for filmmakers with an allusion to filmmakers moving on to make films that demand more of the filmmaker, like dramas. There is also the suggestion that filmmakers can make mistakes and more glaring mistakes in their documentary forays than they  would be allowed to when making drama.</p>
<p>Reading Barnouw&#8217;s history, however, it becomes clear that documentary filmmakers were at the forefront of the history and development of filmmaking from the beginning. The first filmmakers were documentary filmmakers, who, in a sense, laid the foundations for all kinds of filmmaking. This does not mean that these early filmmakers were less sophisticated than those who came later; instead, it means to me, that these filmmakers had to work harder than those who came later in order to understand the medium and to use it to say what they wanted to say.</p>
<p>The documentary filmmakers who were fortunate and privileged enough to be making films in the early twentieth Century, were making films that still inspire and intrigue us today. Not only in terms of the stories they were telling, but also in how they used the camera and co-ordinated the technical teams they worked with. With bulkier equipment and often larger crews than we work with on documentary films today, the pioneering filmmakers were able to capture magical shots, scenes and sequences that we learn from today. These achievements wrought out of the demands of the times suggest that documentary filmmaking is a craft that requires patience, focus and a technical intuitiveness. More a bootcamp than a  nursery school where you learn your ABCs. The point being that even though you could throw someone in the deep end on a documentary film, this is not because it is easier to make a documentary film than it is to make a drama, but perhaps because our society values documentary films less than fiction. The ability to &#8220;never to stop looking, never to stop responding to the world around one,&#8221; the trait Richard Leacock admired in Robert Flaherty and thought the most difficult discipline, is one of the hardest for a first time filmmaker to get to grips with. As the story changes, the filmmaker needs to be thinking about how the changes may be worked into the film and needs to ensure that the footage will make sense of all the unscripted real life drama, while the first time fiction filmmaker does not have this challenge.</p>
<p>The second idea popularly held about documentary films in South Africa that the book made me revisit is the one that tells us that documentary films don&#8217;t make money. The story of documentary from 1895 through to the Second World War is one of a receptive audience and willing sponsors. People were fascinated by the faces and images from the world around them. Documentaries had cinema releases, which were sold out and during World War II, documentary was more popular than fiction. In fact, throughout these heady first fifty years, documentary was more popular than fiction. First of all documentary led the way in technical developments and secondly, it was able to show people themselves, it was able to take them around the world, and it was able to place them at world events as they happened. Documentary was not for a niche market, it was for the world.</p>
<p>From my reading of the book it seems that a growing concern amongst governments (notably American and Russian) and corporations of how they may be portrayed and then perceived by the audience led to a reluctance to sanction and support documentary films.</p>
<blockquote><p>In the postwar years, as multi-national corporations &#8211; largely under American control &#8211; expanded abroad at an unprecendented rate, the drive to control markets, resources, and media went with them.</p>
<p>The beginnings of the cold war were related to this development. Starting shortly after World War II, this confrontation between capitalist and socialist powers involved struggles for markets and resources, but proclaimed itself in ideological terms. On both sides it brought a stiffening of controls over mass media &#8211; with drastic impact on documentary content and style. DOCUMENTARY A History of the Non-Fiction Film by Erik Barnouw, p.221</p></blockquote>
<p>This period of media control in the US we tend to lump under the banner of McCarthyism, even though McCarthy only started his attack on the Office of War Information in early 1950. The earlier suppression of &#8220;un-American activities&#8221; began in 1947 by the US House of  Representatives included the rooting out of &#8220;communism in the film industry.&#8221; Tactics included the blacklisting of uncooperative artists we have seen in films of the period. McCarthy&#8217;s attack followed this, along with the FBI&#8217;s purge of subversive elements within the film industry. Many of these so called subversives were documentary and news filmmakers, who had travelled and reported on the war and on the world. These travels and the reporting meant that these filmmakers had been in contact with the new enemy &#8211; the Russians, the communists.</p>
<p>The changes in the way documentary film was viewed sixty years ago has clearly affected our view of documentary film today. As documentary fell out of favour, distribution channels closed down and there was less money and less support in the form of funding for marketing.  This was the result of concerted efforts and official policies. What we need today is concerted effort and official policy to reverse this legacy.</p>
<p>Maybe documentary film does not have to be the training ground for filmmakers. Maybe if more money were pumped into documentary films, they would actually make money for the investors.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../ashorthistoryofdocumentary/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Power of Documentary Film</title>
		<link>./../../../thepowerofdocumentaryfilm/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../thepowerofdocumentaryfilm/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2010 16:15:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Words on Pictures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Documentary film]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=196</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Soviet cinema, in decline during the 1930&#8217;s, began a renascence during the war, with documentary leading the way. Its hold over audiences, in a land ...]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_199" style="width: 385px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2010/12/FightingInStalingrad.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-199" class="size-full wp-image-199 " title="FightingInStalingrad" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2010/12/FightingInStalingrad.png" alt="Fighting in Stalingrad WWII" width="375" height="283" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2010/12/FightingInStalingrad.png 375w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2010/12/FightingInStalingrad-300x226.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 375px) 100vw, 375px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-199" class="wp-caption-text">Fighting in Stalingrad WWII</p></div>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Soviet cinema, in decline during the 1930&#8217;s, began a renascence during the war, with documentary leading the way. Its hold over audiences, in a land where virtually all families lost members in combat, was incalculable; documentaries and newsreels often seemed the only link with distant loved ones. For many years after the war, on May 3 of each year, a woman in Tashkent laid flowers at the screen of her local cinema. It was where she had her last glimpse of a son.&#8221; DOCUMENTARY &#8211; A HISTORY OF THE NON-FICTION FILM, p. 152 by ERIK BARNOUW</p></blockquote>
<p>What is not clear from this quote is that the woman last saw her son at this cinema in a documentary film.</p>
<p>*Images for this blog post including the thumbnail were found <a title="Incredible Images for You blog" href="http://incredibleimages4u.blogspot.com/2010/06/russia-in-second-world-war-1944.html" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../thepowerofdocumentaryfilm/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>On Documenting</title>
		<link>./../../../ondocumenting/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../ondocumenting/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2010 10:15:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Words on Pictures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[documentary filmmaking]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://attentiontodetail.wordpress.com/?p=732</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Erik Barnouw in his Documentary: A History of the Non-Fiction Film writes this about Polish cinematographer Boleslaw Matuszewski on pages 27 to 29: He recognized ...]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Erik Barnouw in his <em>Documentary: A History of the Non-Fiction Film</em> writes this about Polish cinematographer Boleslaw Matuszewski on pages 27 to 29:</p>
<blockquote><p>He recognized that history does not always happen where one waits for it, and that effects are easier to find and photograph than causes.</p></blockquote>
<p>This makes me wonder whether brilliant documentary filmmaking captures the causes and not only the effects. It allows viewers to understand why something happened or why something is the way it is.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../ondocumenting/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Movie of the Year</title>
		<link>./../../../mymovieoftheyear/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../mymovieoftheyear/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2010 16:27:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspires me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Words on Pictures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bottled Up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Do Osadne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Documentary film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Housing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Italy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[My Perestoika]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Peddler]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://attentiontodetail.wordpress.com/?p=692</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[In the first quarter of 2010 I was a film reader for the 12th Encounters Documentary Film Festival. What this meant was, although I was ...]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the first quarter of 2010 I was a film reader for the 12th Encounters Documentary Film Festival. What this meant was, although I was barely paid, I got to watch about fifty documentary films. Most of them were good and there was a fair number of brilliant films amongst them. My favourites include <em><a href="http://www.bbfilm.tv/eng/?p=386">Housing</a></em> by Federica di Giacomo, <em><a href="http://fest10.sffs.org/films/film_details.php?id=66">The Peddler</a></em> by Lucas Marcheggiano, Eduardo de la Serna and Adriana Yurcovich, <em><a href="http://myperestroika.com/">My Perestroik</a>a</em> by Robin Hessman, <em><a href="http://www.melbournefilmfestival.com.au/films/view?film_id=90855">Do Osadne</a></em> by Marko Skop and <em>Bottled Up</em> by Luiza Faga. In no particular order, even though I have watched <em>Housing</em> three times already and enjoy it each time. None of my favourites made it into the Festival, but they are my favourites and well worth watching, I think.</p>
<p><iframe width="500" height="281" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/x33xgjsnme4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>So, then, there are many movies of the year for 2010, but if I were forced to choose I would have to go with <em>Housing</em>. In South Africa we face issues of housing on a daily basis that some South Africans have tired of hearing about them. When you&#8217;re a middle class South African in South Africa, the issue of people having roofs over their heads can appear to be a particularly South African one inherited from that albatross, apartheid, that hangs tirelessly around South African necks. Our understanding of the politics of housing is a particularly South African understanding. Even though there are white people, few, without roofs to call their own, one has to work hard to see it as a human rights issue and not a black issue, despite it being the direct result of apartheid policies. Not because South Africans do not see black people as human beings, but because we are thoughtlessly plagued by the notion that people are either one or the other. Although, at times this is not so thoughtless because the economic discrepancies that do exist in South Africa, exist along these colour lines and it is the starting point of trying to understand why things are the way they are.</p>
<p>On another level we are aware that there are housing issues all over the world, although we may not know them as intimately as our own. This is the power of documentary films, of brilliant documentary &#8211; they take you straight into a world you would not usually visit and show you ways of being you would otherwise not see. They make you exclaim to yourself &#8211; if not out loud to your fellow movie watchers &#8211; <em>I didn&#8217;t know that! </em></p>
<p><iframe width="500" height="375" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/b-FnpVxNiq0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>The housing issue in <em>Housing</em> is also about a housing shortage and the failure of government to provide for the poor (the issue that governments allow there to be poor people is a topic for another day). The film&#8217;s angle, however, presents the people without houses as the menace. If you have a council house or a council flat in Bari you are fortunate because there are 20 000 families on a waiting list who do not have a house or a flat for themselves. If you have to leave your house or flat for a while, which, depending on your circumstances, may be three hours or a month, you may return to find that your home has been invaded by squatters who now call your home theirs. All the people we meet through the film are scared of losing their homes. As a result their movements are restricted, complicated and often odd.</p>
<p>In <em>Housing</em> the filmmakers had incredible access to their characters allowing us to see things that are almost surreal. We learn about the working class housing shortage in Bari through four main stories. There&#8217;s the forty-odd year old overweight man, who seems to be a loser. He is always moaning and he has nothing positive to say about anything. He is always wearing the same shirt and the one time he goes to the laundromat, he leaves while putting this shirt back on.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s the disabled woman with the disabled daughter, who threatens municipal and council staff that she will gas herself and her daughter if she is unable to do a house swop that allows her to move out of her current flat.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s the pensioner who never leaves her house, has her son-in-law deliver her groceries, has conversations with friends in neighbouring blocks by shouting across narrow concrete yards and has the hairdresser pay her a house visit.</p>
<p>Finally there&#8217;s the man in his late fifties or sixties with a girlfriend &#8211; who reminded me of a chihuahua &#8211; and whose relationship falters because of the housing situation.</p>
<p>What makes <em>Housing</em> brilliant is the decisions the filmmakers made. You could argue that we only get to see what the filmmakers want us to see and there&#8217;s a lot we don&#8217;t get to see. And your argument would be spot on. The filmmakers chose the scenes that would intrigue, engage and perplex us. It is these choices that hold you spellbound throughout the film. Yes, we never see the people who threaten the characters in the film, but we certainly learn to understand how the threat is perceived by our four heroes.</p>
<p>Anyone who holds up a camera when there are people around will know that when the camera appears people change. Some shy away from the camera, others are drawn to the camera and still others play to the camera. Through <em>Housing</em> you sometimes wonder whether the people in the film are playing to the camera and they may well be, but that doesn&#8217;t detract from the impact of the film. You will have this in any documentary film and sometimes it can be clear that people are playing for the camera and that makes you distance yourself from the person, but it doesn&#8217;t happen like this in <em>Housing </em>&#8211; you wonder and then you follow the story.</p>
<p>The way the story is cut together we are constantly hungry for more, hungry to see and to understand. We cannot know why the filmmakers made the choices they did &#8211; in order to know that we would have to have a conversation with them and perhaps know all the footage they shot. When we know all the footage, we may find ourselves making different choices, explaining the housing shortage differently. All we can know is whether we enjoyed the film or not.</p>
<p>It would make me happy if you got to see <em>Housing</em> and the other films in my list. But don&#8217;t do it for me, do it for yourself.</p>
<p>[*The thumgnail image for this post was taken from the Melbourne International Film Festival&#8217;s web site http://miff.com.au/films/]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../mymovieoftheyear/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shutter Island</title>
		<link>./../../../shutterisland/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../shutterisland/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2010 16:21:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Words on Pictures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dennis Lehane]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Leonardi DiCaprio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Ruffalo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Martin Scorsese]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shutter Island]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://attentiontodetail.wordpress.com/?p=504</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[I read Dennis Lehane&#8217;s  &#8216;Shutter Island&#8217; either towards the end of last year or earlier this year. As I neared the end of the thriller, ...]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I read Dennis Lehane&#8217;s  &#8216;Shutter Island&#8217; either towards the end of last year or earlier this year. As I neared the end of the thriller, I started thinking that the story was perfectly suited to a movie. And then, a few weeks later, I learnt that Martin Scorsese had already adapted the book into a screenplay and I started looking forward to the movie.</p>
<p>So, now I&#8217;ve seen the movie and, as with his previous film, &#8216;The Departed&#8217;, I am disappointed. Although this disappointment may be influenced by the fact that I recently read the book, here I try to explain my response.</p>
<p>The movie opens with a white screen as the ferry bringing Ted Daniels and Chuck Aule to Shutter Island passes through the fog that metaphorically represents the unclear world the two will be wading through once they&#8217;re on the Island. I thought this was clever and that the bright white of the fog and the bland grey of the sky and the ferry worked well for what I knew lay ahead. Once we make it through the fog onto the deck, we meet our two main characters watching the approaching island. When the captain ominously warns them about the approaching storm we are treated to a sweeping aerial shot that flies towards Shutter Island. I loved this shot and it moved us very quickly to the main location and into the main story, the only story. The Shutter Island that Scorsese had created was very close to the Shutter Island I had created in my imagination &#8211; the buildings, the guards, the nurses, the orderlies, the activities.</p>
<p>I know that if Scorsese&#8217;s Shutter Island had been very different from my  Shutter Island this would have posed its own problems. As it is,  though, our Shutter Islands are rather similar. I don&#8217;t think that it is  the similarity that prevented me from being drawn into the film, I  think it is more likely the fact that I know the story too well and was  watching the film to make sense of the choices Scorsese had made.</p>
<p>Another thing that troubled me about the film &#8211; and that I am only articulating to myself now as I write &#8211; is that it is almost too perfectly made. The 1950s, when the story is set, is often presented as a time that was very much about sparkling appearances with dark secrets bubbling underneath the surface. Shutter Island the film is true to this and maybe this is the problem. Even though there is a violent storm at the beginning of the film, the little Shutter Island bubble remains neat: the cracked tree tunks are neat and there is very little evidence of havoc wreaked by the storm. The beds in the bunker where everyone bunks the night of the storm are also very neatly lined up and there is little chaos within this shelter. Teddy Daniels scales the cliffs of Shutter Island with nary a scratch to be found on his person, nevermind that scaling those cliffs are near impossible. Okay so the violent inmates break free, but even this is directed in a way that it does not look like close to all hell has broken loose. Maybe this is the genius of Scorsese? I don&#8217;t know if this is what he wanted, but it seems a bit too polished to be real. Of course I don&#8217;t mean documentary real, I mean it doesn&#8217;t create a real enough sense of the imperfect real world to convince me to suspend my disbelief and step into the film as if I were there.</p>
<p>As Martin Scorsese has been making films longer than I have been alive, it is no surprise that he is able to use the tools of the trade to masterful effect and construct perfect shots and beautiful pictures for us to look at. Throughout the film Scorsese also made use of the slightly high angled shot as he followed our main characters about, giving one the sense that something beyond their knowledge was happening, or that someone knew more than they did. Another shot that surprised and excited me was the ocean&#8217;s point of view shot of Ted Daniels in the orderly&#8217;s white uniform diving into the sea. The sequence begins with Ted on the rocky shore, he lifts off, we cut into the ocean&#8217;s pov as Daniels flies over the camera, and then we cut back to the observer&#8217;s perspective from the shore as he slices into the sea. The white outfit flying through the cloudy white sky and then cracking into the white-grey sea made me catch my breath.</p>
<p>Then there are the characters. Ted Daniels as played by Leonardo Cappucino, was all acting and very little character. I snorted during the scene where he discovers the drowned children, drags them one-by-one into his arms, cut to an aerial shot of the water rippling ever wider around the destroyed family and Cappucino opens his mouth to scream that cliched Hollywood, &#8220;Noooooo,&#8221; as he throws his head back towards the heavens. I expected more.</p>
<p>Cappucino&#8217;s accent did not work for me. I was told by my Slacking companion that it was meant to be Bostonian, but the pronunciation of  &#8216;marshall&#8217; (with the first &#8216;a&#8217; as the &#8216;u&#8217; in club) and &#8216;escaped&#8217; (as exscaped) kept sticking in my ear. It was as if those were the two words he had practised and so they had to make sure they got them in the script frequently enough, so we could hear that he really was from Boston.</p>
<p>Overall, it was hard to believe that Cappucino had made it to the point where he inhabited the character and became the character. He still had a few rehearsals to go.</p>
<p>And Mark Ruffalo? He wore this pained Bruce Willis expression through most of the film. I used to like him &#8211; especially after &#8216;In the Cut&#8217; &#8211; but I will have to revisit my opinion of his acting.</p>
<p>But maybe, all this does is expose how far I still have to go as a director. I mean if the film works for most, especially for those who haven&#8217;t read the book, then Scorsese has done a great job of distancing himself from the script and the plot and of being able to judge whether the characters and the set are as they&#8217;re supposed to be.</p>
<p>And this has nothing to do with it, but as this is a blog, not a formal remunerated article, here is something I always wondered, which would be a question directed at Dennis Lehane, not at Martin Scorsese: why give the protagonist such an odd name, like Andrew Laeddis. Is Laeddis a common name in the States? It seems to me that Laeddis would be more suited as the made-up name and Daniels as the genuine name.</p>
<p>*Images used for this post are taken from imbd.com&#8217;s Shutter Island page</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../shutterisland/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Drug of the Nation</title>
		<link>./../../../thedrugofthenation/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../thedrugofthenation/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2009 11:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Quotes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Words on Pictures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cinema]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Penelope Houston]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tv]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://attentiontodetail.wordpress.com/?p=457</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[In 1962, 1963 when she wrote &#8216;The Contemporary Cinema&#8217; Penelope Houston was working at the British Film Institute. In &#8216;The Contemporary Cinema&#8217; she provides an ...]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In 1962, 1963 when she wrote &#8216;The Contemporary Cinema&#8217; Penelope Houston was working at the British Film Institute. In &#8216;The Contemporary Cinema&#8217; she provides an analysis of the context of the development of cinema from the early days of cinema to the 1960s with the introduction of television when she was writing.</p>
<p>In her introduction to the book there is a paragraph I find interesting in terms of how it relates to tv viewing today:</p>
<p><a href="http://attentiontodetail.files.wordpress.com/2009/12/testpatterntext1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-466" title="TestPatternText" src="http://attentiontodetail.files.wordpress.com/2009/12/testpatterntext1.jpg" alt="" width="490" height="321" /></a></p>
<p>She doesn&#8217;t explain what the Pilkington Report revealed, but various Pilkington Reports can be found <a title="Various Pilkington Reports" href="http://hansard.millbanksystems.com/lords/1962/jul/18/the-pilkington-report-on-broadcasting">here</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>[*The thumbnail used for this post was taken from http://smarterthanmatt.blogspot.com]/</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../thedrugofthenation/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Science of Sleep</title>
		<link>./../../../thescienceofsleep/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../thescienceofsleep/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2009 09:55:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Words on Pictures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alain Chabat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charlotte Gainsbourg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gael García Bernal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michel Gondry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Miou-Miou]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science of Sleep]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://attentiontodetail.wordpress.com/?p=269</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8216;The Science of Sleep&#8217; (2006) is Michel Gondry&#8217;s third feature film after &#8216;Human Nature&#8217; and the popular &#8216;Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind&#8217;. It stars ...]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8216;The Science of Sleep&#8217; (2006) is Michel Gondry&#8217;s third feature film after &#8216;Human Nature&#8217; and the popular &#8216;Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind&#8217;. It stars Gael García Bernal, Charlotte Gainsbourg, Alain Chabat, and Miou-Miou.</p>
<div id="attachment_286" style="width: 458px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-286" class="size-full wp-image-286" title="Guy and Stephane" src="http://attentiontodetail.files.wordpress.com/2009/09/scienceofsleep.jpg" alt="Stephan and Guy" width="448" height="252" /><p id="caption-attachment-286" class="wp-caption-text">Guy and Stephane</p></div>
<p><strong>SPOILER ALERT</strong><br />
&#8216;The Science of Sleep&#8217; is the story of Stephane Miroux (García), a graphic artist, whose mother (Miou-Miou) tricks him to return to Paris from Mexico after his father&#8217;s death. The entire film is a joy to watch and further proof &#8211; if you need it &#8211; of Gondry&#8217;s artistic skill at translating what&#8217;s inside his head onto the screen. He translates universal dream experiences in a way that makes you think, <em>okay, I know what&#8217;s going on here.</em> So, when Stephane&#8217;s hands are larger than his body, or he dives out the office window into the sky above the city and starts to swim, or he takes a bath with his only female colleague, Martin, (who has become his secretary in the dream) in cellophane, or he tries to escape the police in his cardboard car (referencing Goddard&#8217;s &#8216;Breathless&#8217;) it all makes sense because it&#8217;s a dream world and we all know how crazy things happen effortlessly and normally in our dreams.</p>
<p>The wonder of Gondry is that there is so much going on. The animation and the live action work together as one world, Stephane&#8217;s world. What happens in the real world influences the dream world: Stephane takes the bath with Martin because Guy (Chabat), the guy at work who has taken him under his wing, constantly alludes to Martin&#8217;s imagined nakedness and lewd things she could do with Stephane.</p>
<p>The script is witty with quotes like these:</p>
<blockquote><p>Tonight I&#8217;ll show you how dreams are prepared &#8230; Stephane at the start of the film on STEPHANE TV</p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>Stephane: It&#8217;s like touching your penis with your left hand.<br />
Stephanie: I don&#8217;t have a penis.<br />
Stephane: But you have a left hand.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: left;">Stephanie: Randomness is very difficult to achieve &#8230; organisation always merges back if you don&#8217;t pay attention.<br />
Stephane: Death to organisation.</p>
<p style="text-align: right;">&#8230; as they try to create the perfect sea with cellophane</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: left;">One of my favourite scenes would be with Stephane and Stephanie playing with huge pieces of cottonwool trying to create clouds for the animated world. Only when Stephane finds the right chords on the piano, do the clouds stay suspended just below the ceiling.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&#8216;The Science of Sleep&#8217; is fun, visually exciting and certainly entertaining. The one thing missing for me, was emotion. There was emotion within the film and you could understand what characters were experiencing because you had probably experienced most of those things yourself. For me, however, I was only an observer and never drawn into the world enough, I didn&#8217;t find myself invested in the characters enough to care what happened to them, I was merely along for the ride.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">The downside of this for me, is that it makes me see all the work that went into making the film, rather than all the fun that was had. When a film draws me in and makes me care about the characters and the entire world on the screen, I am inspired to make something like what I have just seen or just to make something. When I am not drawn into the world this doesn&#8217;t happen. I can appreciate the artistry, or the lack thereof, when I am more distant, but I am not inspired. And this is how Gondry has let me down. His work on this film was clearly inspired with references to other films, books, and his personal life floating onto the screen, but for me it is not inspiring.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">[*Images for this post were found at http://www.clashmusic.com]/</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../thescienceofsleep/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kentridge and Dumas in Conversation</title>
		<link>./../../../kentridgeanddumasinconversation/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../kentridgeanddumasinconversation/index.html#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2009 22:07:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Words on Pictures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Catherine Meyburg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[documetary film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Felix in Exile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marlene Dumas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[William Kentridge]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://attentiontodetail.wordpress.com/?p=224</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[I have just come from seeing &#8216;Kentridge &#38; Dumas in Conversation&#8217;, a film by South African director and editor Catherine Meyburg. The film is showing ...]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have just come from seeing &#8216;Kentridge &amp; Dumas in Conversation&#8217;, a film by South African director and editor Catherine Meyburg. The film is showing at the Encounters Documentary Film Festival in Cape Town. I will only mention in passing my initial apprehension when I saw that the filmmaker had used the ampersand in the title of the film, instead of spelling out the word and. I doubt there was any pressure to hurry and finish the title, and even though the ampersand by itself is neat and elegant, I always find it ugly and repressed amidst other words and a sign of carelessness in the user.</p>
<p>I will also mention in passing that I was one of three black people &#8211; staff discounted &#8211; at the film. And if I hadn&#8217;t gone, there would only have been two at the screening &#8230;</p>
<p>I went to see the film because I would like to make a film about an artist friend of mine. Kentridge and Dumas (that&#8217;s William Kentridge and Marlene Dumas) spend most of the film talking about their processes and how certain elements and themes came about. It certainly is illuminating to hear Dumas talk about Chinese and Japanese pornographic paintings; and it is insightful to hear Kentridge explain why he rides around naked in his studio on his son&#8217;s little bicycle.</p>
<p>They talk about perspective and interpretation, and give concrete examples of how different people interpret their works differently because of each person&#8217;s context. I was pleased to hear each artist talk about choosing the easier way to do things, e.g. when Kentridge thinks about drawing and animating a horse in his film &#8216;Felix in Exile&#8217; he realises how much work this will be and decides to replace the horse with a fish. Sometimes, I believe, taking the easy way out works better in the long run.</p>
<p>Overall the film was interesting and the interview location was well chosen, but the film lacked vitality, which I think could have been enhanced through more locations and more detail. I could be inclined towards more locations because I am working on a series where a variety of locations in made-for-tv documentaries helps make the people and the story more dynamic. Kentridge and Dumas are certainly interesting and most people would have gone to see the film because they are interested in the characters and their works. The bulk of the film, however, happens in a well-lit white room with neat green grass outside the windows. The location is white and sparse, the artists wear white and black and everything feels minimal and vast &#8211; as if the location were a canvas, waiting for the artists to place their marks (characters) on it.</p>
<p>This interview location feels like a reflection of Kentridge&#8217;s personality, however. When we see Kentridge in his studio, it is neat and organised, while Dumas&#8217; studio is cluttered, she works on the floor, and you catch a glimpse of a mattress where she probably sleeps amidst her work. There are hints of Dumas having an unruly energy and this comes across rather definitely through her hair, the busy studio and the way she talks, but I find this aspect of her personality, which contrasts Kentridge&#8217;s, is not afforded equal visual importance.</p>
<p>Most of the time we are inside, although there are some exterior shots around Kentridge&#8217;s house and some shots in a town somewhere in Europe &#8211; although I don&#8217;t think it is mentioned where this is. The film is bracketed by a social event, where in the beginning we see Dumas arriving at Kentridge&#8217;s home and presenting him with a bottle of wine while food is being prepared in the kitchen; and at the end of the film, they are seated around a long dinner table with about ten other people, eating the food and drinking the wine suggested at the start of the film.</p>
<p>So, although their works and processes are dynamic, the dynamism does not come across visually. The film lacks energy for me and I wish it were more alive. I do not think this is the fault of the characters, nor a flaw of their works. I think it is more a shortcoming of the direction and the visuals used to convey the subject.</p>
<p>There are enough examples of the artists&#8217; works, but we don&#8217;t get to see much detail. It could be that the artists did not want to show too much detail of their works &#8211; I don&#8217;t know &#8211; but that is something that I miss. I would think that one way to honour two of South Africa&#8217;s greatest exports and their works would be to get under the skins of the canvasses in a sense. This detail would have helped to energise the film.</p>
<p>I was surprised that the filmmaker had allowed unwanted bits of audio to creep into the film. For example, in one scene Dumas starts talking about something, but at the beginning you can still hear her finishing off another thought of the previous sentence. I know how hard it is to make a film and how rigorous you have to be about every little thing; I don&#8217;t usually get this right, and I always hope that not too many people notice. I had expected (setting myself up for disappointment, no doubt) that a film about creative and technical heavyweights would exact more creative and technical rigour than I fear I could deliver.</p>
<p>I also found the music screamingly loud &#8211; this could have been a problem with the cinema&#8217;s audio levels, however.</p>
<p>Most of the shortcomings in the film feel as if they were results of constraints imposed by funding, format, or broadcast requirements. So, it feels as if the film could have been longer, that we could have had more of a sense of Dumas&#8217; personality if the filmmaker had had a bigger budget to spend more time in Holland; that there could have been more locations if there had been more money and more time to film; that there could have been more detail shot of the works had there been more money for better lenses.</p>
<p>But it is a film worth seeing and I am glad that this film has been made and that I had the chance to see it! Thank you Catherine Meyburg.</p>
<p>[*The thumbnail image for this post was taken from http://www.internationalfilmguide.com/ where you can also see another review of the film.]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../kentridgeanddumasinconversation/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
