<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Documentary film &#8211; Accidental Films and TV</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>Documentary Film and TV Productions</description>
	<lastBuildDate>
	Tue, 31 Oct 2017 15:56:54 +0000	</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.1.6</generator>
	<item>
		<title>A Short History of Documentary</title>
		<link>./../../../ashorthistoryofdocumentary/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../ashorthistoryofdocumentary/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 03:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Words on Pictures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Documentary film]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=213</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Erik Barnouw&#8217;s Documentary: A History of the Non-Fiction Film is a satisfying read. The book begins with French astronomer Pierre Jules Cesar Jansen&#8217;s experiments to ...]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Erik Barnouw&#8217;s <em>Documentary: A History of the Non-Fiction Film</em> is a satisfying read. The book begins with French astronomer Pierre Jules Cesar Jansen&#8217;s experiments to record the passage of Venus around the sun, the more well-known attempts of photographer Eadward Muybridge to examine the movement of race horses as precisely as possible, and the young Louis Lumiere&#8217;s invention of the <em>cinematographe</em> and its subsequent world domination as it showed themselves and the world to audiences around the globe. We meet Robert and Frances Flaherty, John Grierson, Dziga Vertov, Esfir Shub, Alberto Cavalcanti, Joris Ivens, Leni Riefenstahl, Humphrey Jennings and so many more &#8230;</p>
<p>The stories of social, technical and economic developments are integral to how these filmmakers came to and influenced documentary filmmaking. I was especially intrigued to learn how the changes over the years, influenced by the political climate around the world, affected the craft and how we have inherited that history in South Africa.</p>
<p>Working in television and video production for the past eleven years I am aware that documentary has a secondary status to that of fiction, or drama in South Africa. It is often said that documentary is the training ground for filmmakers with an allusion to filmmakers moving on to make films that demand more of the filmmaker, like dramas. There is also the suggestion that filmmakers can make mistakes and more glaring mistakes in their documentary forays than they  would be allowed to when making drama.</p>
<p>Reading Barnouw&#8217;s history, however, it becomes clear that documentary filmmakers were at the forefront of the history and development of filmmaking from the beginning. The first filmmakers were documentary filmmakers, who, in a sense, laid the foundations for all kinds of filmmaking. This does not mean that these early filmmakers were less sophisticated than those who came later; instead, it means to me, that these filmmakers had to work harder than those who came later in order to understand the medium and to use it to say what they wanted to say.</p>
<p>The documentary filmmakers who were fortunate and privileged enough to be making films in the early twentieth Century, were making films that still inspire and intrigue us today. Not only in terms of the stories they were telling, but also in how they used the camera and co-ordinated the technical teams they worked with. With bulkier equipment and often larger crews than we work with on documentary films today, the pioneering filmmakers were able to capture magical shots, scenes and sequences that we learn from today. These achievements wrought out of the demands of the times suggest that documentary filmmaking is a craft that requires patience, focus and a technical intuitiveness. More a bootcamp than a  nursery school where you learn your ABCs. The point being that even though you could throw someone in the deep end on a documentary film, this is not because it is easier to make a documentary film than it is to make a drama, but perhaps because our society values documentary films less than fiction. The ability to &#8220;never to stop looking, never to stop responding to the world around one,&#8221; the trait Richard Leacock admired in Robert Flaherty and thought the most difficult discipline, is one of the hardest for a first time filmmaker to get to grips with. As the story changes, the filmmaker needs to be thinking about how the changes may be worked into the film and needs to ensure that the footage will make sense of all the unscripted real life drama, while the first time fiction filmmaker does not have this challenge.</p>
<p>The second idea popularly held about documentary films in South Africa that the book made me revisit is the one that tells us that documentary films don&#8217;t make money. The story of documentary from 1895 through to the Second World War is one of a receptive audience and willing sponsors. People were fascinated by the faces and images from the world around them. Documentaries had cinema releases, which were sold out and during World War II, documentary was more popular than fiction. In fact, throughout these heady first fifty years, documentary was more popular than fiction. First of all documentary led the way in technical developments and secondly, it was able to show people themselves, it was able to take them around the world, and it was able to place them at world events as they happened. Documentary was not for a niche market, it was for the world.</p>
<p>From my reading of the book it seems that a growing concern amongst governments (notably American and Russian) and corporations of how they may be portrayed and then perceived by the audience led to a reluctance to sanction and support documentary films.</p>
<blockquote><p>In the postwar years, as multi-national corporations &#8211; largely under American control &#8211; expanded abroad at an unprecendented rate, the drive to control markets, resources, and media went with them.</p>
<p>The beginnings of the cold war were related to this development. Starting shortly after World War II, this confrontation between capitalist and socialist powers involved struggles for markets and resources, but proclaimed itself in ideological terms. On both sides it brought a stiffening of controls over mass media &#8211; with drastic impact on documentary content and style. DOCUMENTARY A History of the Non-Fiction Film by Erik Barnouw, p.221</p></blockquote>
<p>This period of media control in the US we tend to lump under the banner of McCarthyism, even though McCarthy only started his attack on the Office of War Information in early 1950. The earlier suppression of &#8220;un-American activities&#8221; began in 1947 by the US House of  Representatives included the rooting out of &#8220;communism in the film industry.&#8221; Tactics included the blacklisting of uncooperative artists we have seen in films of the period. McCarthy&#8217;s attack followed this, along with the FBI&#8217;s purge of subversive elements within the film industry. Many of these so called subversives were documentary and news filmmakers, who had travelled and reported on the war and on the world. These travels and the reporting meant that these filmmakers had been in contact with the new enemy &#8211; the Russians, the communists.</p>
<p>The changes in the way documentary film was viewed sixty years ago has clearly affected our view of documentary film today. As documentary fell out of favour, distribution channels closed down and there was less money and less support in the form of funding for marketing.  This was the result of concerted efforts and official policies. What we need today is concerted effort and official policy to reverse this legacy.</p>
<p>Maybe documentary film does not have to be the training ground for filmmakers. Maybe if more money were pumped into documentary films, they would actually make money for the investors.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../ashorthistoryofdocumentary/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Power of Documentary Film</title>
		<link>./../../../thepowerofdocumentaryfilm/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../thepowerofdocumentaryfilm/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2010 16:15:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Words on Pictures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Documentary film]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=196</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Soviet cinema, in decline during the 1930&#8217;s, began a renascence during the war, with documentary leading the way. Its hold over audiences, in a land ...]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_199" style="width: 385px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2010/12/FightingInStalingrad.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-199" class="size-full wp-image-199 " title="FightingInStalingrad" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2010/12/FightingInStalingrad.png" alt="Fighting in Stalingrad WWII" width="375" height="283" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2010/12/FightingInStalingrad.png 375w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2010/12/FightingInStalingrad-300x226.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 375px) 100vw, 375px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-199" class="wp-caption-text">Fighting in Stalingrad WWII</p></div>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Soviet cinema, in decline during the 1930&#8217;s, began a renascence during the war, with documentary leading the way. Its hold over audiences, in a land where virtually all families lost members in combat, was incalculable; documentaries and newsreels often seemed the only link with distant loved ones. For many years after the war, on May 3 of each year, a woman in Tashkent laid flowers at the screen of her local cinema. It was where she had her last glimpse of a son.&#8221; DOCUMENTARY &#8211; A HISTORY OF THE NON-FICTION FILM, p. 152 by ERIK BARNOUW</p></blockquote>
<p>What is not clear from this quote is that the woman last saw her son at this cinema in a documentary film.</p>
<p>*Images for this blog post including the thumbnail were found <a title="Incredible Images for You blog" href="http://incredibleimages4u.blogspot.com/2010/06/russia-in-second-world-war-1944.html" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../thepowerofdocumentaryfilm/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Movie of the Year</title>
		<link>./../../../mymovieoftheyear/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../mymovieoftheyear/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2010 16:27:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspires me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Words on Pictures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bottled Up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Do Osadne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Documentary film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Housing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Italy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[My Perestoika]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Peddler]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://attentiontodetail.wordpress.com/?p=692</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[In the first quarter of 2010 I was a film reader for the 12th Encounters Documentary Film Festival. What this meant was, although I was ...]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the first quarter of 2010 I was a film reader for the 12th Encounters Documentary Film Festival. What this meant was, although I was barely paid, I got to watch about fifty documentary films. Most of them were good and there was a fair number of brilliant films amongst them. My favourites include <em><a href="http://www.bbfilm.tv/eng/?p=386">Housing</a></em> by Federica di Giacomo, <em><a href="http://fest10.sffs.org/films/film_details.php?id=66">The Peddler</a></em> by Lucas Marcheggiano, Eduardo de la Serna and Adriana Yurcovich, <em><a href="http://myperestroika.com/">My Perestroik</a>a</em> by Robin Hessman, <em><a href="http://www.melbournefilmfestival.com.au/films/view?film_id=90855">Do Osadne</a></em> by Marko Skop and <em>Bottled Up</em> by Luiza Faga. In no particular order, even though I have watched <em>Housing</em> three times already and enjoy it each time. None of my favourites made it into the Festival, but they are my favourites and well worth watching, I think.</p>
<p><iframe width="500" height="281" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/x33xgjsnme4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>So, then, there are many movies of the year for 2010, but if I were forced to choose I would have to go with <em>Housing</em>. In South Africa we face issues of housing on a daily basis that some South Africans have tired of hearing about them. When you&#8217;re a middle class South African in South Africa, the issue of people having roofs over their heads can appear to be a particularly South African one inherited from that albatross, apartheid, that hangs tirelessly around South African necks. Our understanding of the politics of housing is a particularly South African understanding. Even though there are white people, few, without roofs to call their own, one has to work hard to see it as a human rights issue and not a black issue, despite it being the direct result of apartheid policies. Not because South Africans do not see black people as human beings, but because we are thoughtlessly plagued by the notion that people are either one or the other. Although, at times this is not so thoughtless because the economic discrepancies that do exist in South Africa, exist along these colour lines and it is the starting point of trying to understand why things are the way they are.</p>
<p>On another level we are aware that there are housing issues all over the world, although we may not know them as intimately as our own. This is the power of documentary films, of brilliant documentary &#8211; they take you straight into a world you would not usually visit and show you ways of being you would otherwise not see. They make you exclaim to yourself &#8211; if not out loud to your fellow movie watchers &#8211; <em>I didn&#8217;t know that! </em></p>
<p><iframe width="500" height="375" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/b-FnpVxNiq0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>The housing issue in <em>Housing</em> is also about a housing shortage and the failure of government to provide for the poor (the issue that governments allow there to be poor people is a topic for another day). The film&#8217;s angle, however, presents the people without houses as the menace. If you have a council house or a council flat in Bari you are fortunate because there are 20 000 families on a waiting list who do not have a house or a flat for themselves. If you have to leave your house or flat for a while, which, depending on your circumstances, may be three hours or a month, you may return to find that your home has been invaded by squatters who now call your home theirs. All the people we meet through the film are scared of losing their homes. As a result their movements are restricted, complicated and often odd.</p>
<p>In <em>Housing</em> the filmmakers had incredible access to their characters allowing us to see things that are almost surreal. We learn about the working class housing shortage in Bari through four main stories. There&#8217;s the forty-odd year old overweight man, who seems to be a loser. He is always moaning and he has nothing positive to say about anything. He is always wearing the same shirt and the one time he goes to the laundromat, he leaves while putting this shirt back on.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s the disabled woman with the disabled daughter, who threatens municipal and council staff that she will gas herself and her daughter if she is unable to do a house swop that allows her to move out of her current flat.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s the pensioner who never leaves her house, has her son-in-law deliver her groceries, has conversations with friends in neighbouring blocks by shouting across narrow concrete yards and has the hairdresser pay her a house visit.</p>
<p>Finally there&#8217;s the man in his late fifties or sixties with a girlfriend &#8211; who reminded me of a chihuahua &#8211; and whose relationship falters because of the housing situation.</p>
<p>What makes <em>Housing</em> brilliant is the decisions the filmmakers made. You could argue that we only get to see what the filmmakers want us to see and there&#8217;s a lot we don&#8217;t get to see. And your argument would be spot on. The filmmakers chose the scenes that would intrigue, engage and perplex us. It is these choices that hold you spellbound throughout the film. Yes, we never see the people who threaten the characters in the film, but we certainly learn to understand how the threat is perceived by our four heroes.</p>
<p>Anyone who holds up a camera when there are people around will know that when the camera appears people change. Some shy away from the camera, others are drawn to the camera and still others play to the camera. Through <em>Housing</em> you sometimes wonder whether the people in the film are playing to the camera and they may well be, but that doesn&#8217;t detract from the impact of the film. You will have this in any documentary film and sometimes it can be clear that people are playing for the camera and that makes you distance yourself from the person, but it doesn&#8217;t happen like this in <em>Housing </em>&#8211; you wonder and then you follow the story.</p>
<p>The way the story is cut together we are constantly hungry for more, hungry to see and to understand. We cannot know why the filmmakers made the choices they did &#8211; in order to know that we would have to have a conversation with them and perhaps know all the footage they shot. When we know all the footage, we may find ourselves making different choices, explaining the housing shortage differently. All we can know is whether we enjoyed the film or not.</p>
<p>It would make me happy if you got to see <em>Housing</em> and the other films in my list. But don&#8217;t do it for me, do it for yourself.</p>
<p>[*The thumgnail image for this post was taken from the Melbourne International Film Festival&#8217;s web site http://miff.com.au/films/]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../mymovieoftheyear/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
