<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Inspires me &#8211; Accidental Films and TV</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>Documentary Film and TV Productions</description>
	<lastBuildDate>
	Tue, 31 Oct 2017 15:56:54 +0000	</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.1.6</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Feminism Across the Globe</title>
		<link>./../../../feminism-across-the-globe/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../feminism-across-the-globe/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 09:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[21st Century World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspires me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Work]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=1357</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Around mid-February we were contacted by Hisham Ashour who is studying Communication at Northwestern University in Qatar.]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-1360 size-full" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2017/02/HishamAshour.jpg" width="640" height="350" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2017/02/HishamAshour.jpg 640w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2017/02/HishamAshour-300x164.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Around mid-February 2017 we were contacted by Hisham Ashour who is studying Communication at Northwestern University in Qatar. Hisham and his group were interested to learn more about <em>Engender</em>, especially with regards to the intersection of race and feminism in South African media.</span></p>
<p>He is interested in the representation of feminism on TV because it is a topic which has recently become more and more relevant globally as media has made access to information around equality much easier than before. Another reason for his interest in <em>Engender</em> was that he was looking at media which was neither mainstream American nor mainstream European. (<em>Engender</em> was broadcast on the community TV platforms Cape Town TV and 1KZN TV in South Africa) The broad goal of his research was to complete a textual analysis along with the research to see how the themes of race and gender were conveyed. This will be part of his group&#8217;s presentation for their class called Understanding Media Contexts.</p>
<p>Hisham says they were interested in feminism because they believe it is often misunderstood. They also aimed to compare and contrast the different issues feminists face abroad and their media approaches.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../feminism-across-the-globe/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Engender</title>
		<link>./../../../engender/index.html</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 19:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[21st Century World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspires me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Work]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=1193</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Engender is a feminist magazine TV programme that encourages South Africans to be bold and create the society we read about in our Constitution.]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/09/EngenderLogoAFWebsite1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1215" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/09/EngenderLogoAFWebsite1.jpg" alt="Engender Broadcast Times" width="640" height="360" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/09/EngenderLogoAFWebsite1.jpg 640w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/09/EngenderLogoAFWebsite1-300x169.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></p>
<p><em>Engender</em> is a feminist magazine TV programme that encourages South Africans to be bold and create the society we read about in our Constitution. We explore and expose gender inequality in society with the aim of making ours a better world for everyone, including our daughters and sons.</p>
<p>Our three part pilot examines society and argues that Feminism is still needed in a country hailed for its progressive Constitution, and in a world where we can communicate instantly with friends in different time zones.Despite policy and technological advances, we struggle to advance into a lived experience where we are treated equally regardless of where we place ourselves on the gender continuum, where boys are not discouraged from pursuing ballet, or girls are allowed to be raucous, where men may express their vulnerabilities and women may be confident without being called <em>aggressive</em> or <em>feisty</em>.</p>
<p><a href="./../../../femi-what/index.html">EPISODE 1</a> explores the origins of feminism, unpacks what feminism is and what it is not, and how feminist action has changed society globally and locally in South Africa.</p>
<p><a href="./../../../ways-of-seeing/index.html">EPISODE 2</a> examines the way media represent people through a gendered lens that normalises stereotypes about people based on perceived genders and sexualities.</p>
<p><a href="./../../../index.html?p=1322">EPISODE 3</a> grapples with the complexity of intersectional feminism to show how race, class, sex, age, and ablism intersect or interlock to multiply the effects of prejudice on an individual.</p>
<p><em>Engender</em> was broadcast on Cape Town Community TV during the 16 Days of Activism in 2015.</p>
<p>We hope you enjoy the programme and that it inspires debate within your network.</p>
<p>Read the post, <em><a href="./../../../engendering-a-better-world/index.html">Engendering a better world</a></em>.</p>
<p>Read the post, <em><a href="./../../../coming-together-to-challenge-patriarchy/index.html">Coming together to challenge patriarchy</a></em>.</p>
<p>Why don&#8217;t you like us on <a href="https://www.facebook.com/engendersa">Facebook</a> and follow us on <a href="https://twitter.com/engenderSA">Twitter</a>.</p>
<p>The three part pilot is funded by the <a href="https://za.boell.org/">Heinrich Boell Foundation</a>.</p>
<p><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/09/HBS-logo-1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1217" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/09/HBS-logo-1.jpg" alt="HBS logo" width="541" height="266" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/09/HBS-logo-1.jpg 541w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/09/HBS-logo-1-300x148.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 541px) 100vw, 541px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Train 3505</title>
		<link>./../../../train-3505/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../train-3505/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2011 11:33:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspires me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Justin Joshua Davy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[My Town Short Film Competition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Train 3505]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=844</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Train 3505 was a submission to the Documentary Filmmakers&#8217; Association&#8217;s My Town Short Film Competition in 2011. The film was shot and edited by Justin ...]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe width="500" height="281" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/woyOo4ZfHPg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><em>Train 3505</em> was a submission to the Documentary Filmmakers&#8217; Association&#8217;s <em>My Town Short Film Competition</em> in 2011. The film was shot and edited by <a title="Justin Joshua Davy's blog" href="http://justindavy.wordpress.com/">Justin Joshua Davy</a>, who worked with me at Accidental Films and TV as an intern from October 2010 &#8211; April 2011.</p>
<p>I like the way Justin lets us feel the train and its occupants before he takes us inside. As we travel through the early morning landscape, we hear the sounds of the train on the rails along with the sounds coming from inside the train. Maybe it&#8217;s because I find travelling on a train quite lulling, or maybe it&#8217;s the moody early morning shots, or maybe it&#8217;s the repetitive sounds &#8211; whatever the cause, in the first 30 seconds of the film I am already transported into the film and a part of it.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a powerful story of the daily commute of 700 000 South Africans. I hope you enjoy it!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../train-3505/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meeting David Goldblatt</title>
		<link>./../../../meetingdavidgoldblatt/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../meetingdavidgoldblatt/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2010 20:23:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Inspires me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Goldblatt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LEAP School of Science and Maths]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Realistic]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=175</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[When I was working on Masupatsela Series I through Free Range Films, one of my favourite stories was the one I did with David Goldblatt. ...]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I was working on Masupatsela Series I through Free Range Films, one of my favourite stories was <a title="To blog at Free Range Films" href="http://www.freerangefilms.co.za/new-posts/coverstory/" target="_blank">the one I did with David Goldblatt</a>. Not only because I love looking at his photographs, but also partly because David Goldblatt was someone I had heard about before working on the series; and partly because of the unexpected way his photography connected with HIV and AIDS amongst the home based care, AIDS clinics and other HIV and AIDS support structures we featured around South Africa. We wanted to show unique ways that people were confronting the challenge of living with HIV and AIDS, and his way was truly unique in my mind.</p>
<p><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/19426737?title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0&amp;color=7e2525" width="600" height="480" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>In Masupatsela Series II my top two projects were <a title="Opens Realistic web site in a new tab" href="http://realisticcbo.org/" target="_blank">Realistic</a> in Gugulethu and <a title="Opens LEAP web site in a new tab" href="http://www.leapschool.org.za/" target="_blank">LEAP Science and Maths School</a> in Pinelands. Both organisations are doing work that inspires and moves me. What this means for me is that if I can be involved in these projects in any way, I will be.</p>
<p>Last week, therefore, I was at Realistic to meet with Ncamile Solomon Madikane, the founder and director of Realistic to discuss a project we could collaborate on. I walked through the doors and found <a title="David Goldblatt at The Goodman Gallery" href="http://www.goodman-gallery.com/artists/davidgoldblatt" target="_blank">David Goldblatt</a> sitting in the waiting area. He explained to me the project he was working on. As I had been the first time when listening to him explain his motivation for that project back in 2007, I was struck once again by this man. There he was, about forty years older than me and still caring enough about the world and the people in it to follow his inspiration and keep on keeping on. At eighty years old he continues to try to make sense of the world &#8211; one man, his lenses and his camper.</p>
<p>I want to be like David Goldblatt when I&#8217;m big!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../meetingdavidgoldblatt/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Movie of the Year</title>
		<link>./../../../mymovieoftheyear/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../mymovieoftheyear/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2010 16:27:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspires me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Words on Pictures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bottled Up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Do Osadne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Documentary film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Housing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Italy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[My Perestoika]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Peddler]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://attentiontodetail.wordpress.com/?p=692</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[In the first quarter of 2010 I was a film reader for the 12th Encounters Documentary Film Festival. What this meant was, although I was ...]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the first quarter of 2010 I was a film reader for the 12th Encounters Documentary Film Festival. What this meant was, although I was barely paid, I got to watch about fifty documentary films. Most of them were good and there was a fair number of brilliant films amongst them. My favourites include <em><a href="http://www.bbfilm.tv/eng/?p=386">Housing</a></em> by Federica di Giacomo, <em><a href="http://fest10.sffs.org/films/film_details.php?id=66">The Peddler</a></em> by Lucas Marcheggiano, Eduardo de la Serna and Adriana Yurcovich, <em><a href="http://myperestroika.com/">My Perestroik</a>a</em> by Robin Hessman, <em><a href="http://www.melbournefilmfestival.com.au/films/view?film_id=90855">Do Osadne</a></em> by Marko Skop and <em>Bottled Up</em> by Luiza Faga. In no particular order, even though I have watched <em>Housing</em> three times already and enjoy it each time. None of my favourites made it into the Festival, but they are my favourites and well worth watching, I think.</p>
<p><iframe width="500" height="281" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/x33xgjsnme4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>So, then, there are many movies of the year for 2010, but if I were forced to choose I would have to go with <em>Housing</em>. In South Africa we face issues of housing on a daily basis that some South Africans have tired of hearing about them. When you&#8217;re a middle class South African in South Africa, the issue of people having roofs over their heads can appear to be a particularly South African one inherited from that albatross, apartheid, that hangs tirelessly around South African necks. Our understanding of the politics of housing is a particularly South African understanding. Even though there are white people, few, without roofs to call their own, one has to work hard to see it as a human rights issue and not a black issue, despite it being the direct result of apartheid policies. Not because South Africans do not see black people as human beings, but because we are thoughtlessly plagued by the notion that people are either one or the other. Although, at times this is not so thoughtless because the economic discrepancies that do exist in South Africa, exist along these colour lines and it is the starting point of trying to understand why things are the way they are.</p>
<p>On another level we are aware that there are housing issues all over the world, although we may not know them as intimately as our own. This is the power of documentary films, of brilliant documentary &#8211; they take you straight into a world you would not usually visit and show you ways of being you would otherwise not see. They make you exclaim to yourself &#8211; if not out loud to your fellow movie watchers &#8211; <em>I didn&#8217;t know that! </em></p>
<p><iframe width="500" height="375" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/b-FnpVxNiq0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>The housing issue in <em>Housing</em> is also about a housing shortage and the failure of government to provide for the poor (the issue that governments allow there to be poor people is a topic for another day). The film&#8217;s angle, however, presents the people without houses as the menace. If you have a council house or a council flat in Bari you are fortunate because there are 20 000 families on a waiting list who do not have a house or a flat for themselves. If you have to leave your house or flat for a while, which, depending on your circumstances, may be three hours or a month, you may return to find that your home has been invaded by squatters who now call your home theirs. All the people we meet through the film are scared of losing their homes. As a result their movements are restricted, complicated and often odd.</p>
<p>In <em>Housing</em> the filmmakers had incredible access to their characters allowing us to see things that are almost surreal. We learn about the working class housing shortage in Bari through four main stories. There&#8217;s the forty-odd year old overweight man, who seems to be a loser. He is always moaning and he has nothing positive to say about anything. He is always wearing the same shirt and the one time he goes to the laundromat, he leaves while putting this shirt back on.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s the disabled woman with the disabled daughter, who threatens municipal and council staff that she will gas herself and her daughter if she is unable to do a house swop that allows her to move out of her current flat.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s the pensioner who never leaves her house, has her son-in-law deliver her groceries, has conversations with friends in neighbouring blocks by shouting across narrow concrete yards and has the hairdresser pay her a house visit.</p>
<p>Finally there&#8217;s the man in his late fifties or sixties with a girlfriend &#8211; who reminded me of a chihuahua &#8211; and whose relationship falters because of the housing situation.</p>
<p>What makes <em>Housing</em> brilliant is the decisions the filmmakers made. You could argue that we only get to see what the filmmakers want us to see and there&#8217;s a lot we don&#8217;t get to see. And your argument would be spot on. The filmmakers chose the scenes that would intrigue, engage and perplex us. It is these choices that hold you spellbound throughout the film. Yes, we never see the people who threaten the characters in the film, but we certainly learn to understand how the threat is perceived by our four heroes.</p>
<p>Anyone who holds up a camera when there are people around will know that when the camera appears people change. Some shy away from the camera, others are drawn to the camera and still others play to the camera. Through <em>Housing</em> you sometimes wonder whether the people in the film are playing to the camera and they may well be, but that doesn&#8217;t detract from the impact of the film. You will have this in any documentary film and sometimes it can be clear that people are playing for the camera and that makes you distance yourself from the person, but it doesn&#8217;t happen like this in <em>Housing </em>&#8211; you wonder and then you follow the story.</p>
<p>The way the story is cut together we are constantly hungry for more, hungry to see and to understand. We cannot know why the filmmakers made the choices they did &#8211; in order to know that we would have to have a conversation with them and perhaps know all the footage they shot. When we know all the footage, we may find ourselves making different choices, explaining the housing shortage differently. All we can know is whether we enjoyed the film or not.</p>
<p>It would make me happy if you got to see <em>Housing</em> and the other films in my list. But don&#8217;t do it for me, do it for yourself.</p>
<p>[*The thumgnail image for this post was taken from the Melbourne International Film Festival&#8217;s web site http://miff.com.au/films/]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../mymovieoftheyear/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
