<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Television &#8211; Accidental Films and TV</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>Documentary Film and TV Productions</description>
	<lastBuildDate>
	Tue, 31 Oct 2017 15:56:54 +0000	</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.1.6</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Feminism Across the Globe</title>
		<link>./../../../feminism-across-the-globe/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../feminism-across-the-globe/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 09:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[21st Century World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspires me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Work]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=1357</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Around mid-February we were contacted by Hisham Ashour who is studying Communication at Northwestern University in Qatar.]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-1360 size-full" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2017/02/HishamAshour.jpg" width="640" height="350" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2017/02/HishamAshour.jpg 640w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2017/02/HishamAshour-300x164.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Around mid-February 2017 we were contacted by Hisham Ashour who is studying Communication at Northwestern University in Qatar. Hisham and his group were interested to learn more about <em>Engender</em>, especially with regards to the intersection of race and feminism in South African media.</span></p>
<p>He is interested in the representation of feminism on TV because it is a topic which has recently become more and more relevant globally as media has made access to information around equality much easier than before. Another reason for his interest in <em>Engender</em> was that he was looking at media which was neither mainstream American nor mainstream European. (<em>Engender</em> was broadcast on the community TV platforms Cape Town TV and 1KZN TV in South Africa) The broad goal of his research was to complete a textual analysis along with the research to see how the themes of race and gender were conveyed. This will be part of his group&#8217;s presentation for their class called Understanding Media Contexts.</p>
<p>Hisham says they were interested in feminism because they believe it is often misunderstood. They also aimed to compare and contrast the different issues feminists face abroad and their media approaches.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../feminism-across-the-globe/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Femi-What??!</title>
		<link>./../../../femi-what/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../femi-what/index.html#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 12:49:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[21st Century World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Work]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=1306</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[PRESENTERS Ayanda Nabe &#124; Helga Jansen-Daugbjerg PANELISTS Gertrude Fester &#124; Dela Gwala &#124; Joy Watson RESEARCHER &#124; SCRIPTWRITER Erna Curry PRODUCER &#124; DIRECTOR Tina-Louise Smith]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/182676101?color=e2bc3f&amp;title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>PRESENTERS<br />
Ayanda Nabe | Helga Jansen-Daugbjerg</p>
<p>PANELISTS<br />
Gertrude Fester | Dela Gwala | Joy Watson</p>
<p>RESEARCHER | SCRIPTWRITER<br />
Erna Curry</p>
<p>PRODUCER | DIRECTOR<br />
Tina-Louise Smith</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../femi-what/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mr Table Tennis Film Review</title>
		<link>./../../../mr-table-tennis-film-review/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../mr-table-tennis-film-review/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 09:24:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Work]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=1248</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[This is a rare glimpse into the world of professional players, and their backyard beginnings ...]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2016/06/MrTTTrophies01.png"><img class="alignnone wp-image-1250" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2016/06/MrTTTrophies01.png" alt="MrTTTrophies01" width="600" height="339" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2016/06/MrTTTrophies01.png 1022w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2016/06/MrTTTrophies01-300x169.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></a></p>
<p>The intensity of table tennis players, slammed me like one of the balls Pedro Meyer was so fond of breaking in front of his opponents. Watching this local table tennis legend talk about his love of the sport infected me with a twitching of hands &#8211; looking for a bat.</p>
<p>A master tactician, a superb player and Western Province Captain, deserves the acknowledgement this documentary gives him. This is a rare glimpse into the world of professional players, and their backyard beginnings, from Lansdowne to London, Bishop Lavis to Sweden. The dreams and the means to achieve them, this is what he coached, along with commitment and joy.</p>
<p>Athlete, father and husband but first always Mr Table Tennis.</p>
<p>Review by <strong>Kimbal Schütt</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../mr-table-tennis-film-review/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Coming together to challenge patriarchy</title>
		<link>./../../../coming-together-to-challenge-patriarchy/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../coming-together-to-challenge-patriarchy/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 09:11:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[21st Century World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Work]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=1227</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[When I started working doing the research for the three pilot episodes of Engender, I immediately felt the energy of people coming together to tackle ...]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I started working doing the research for the three pilot episodes of <em>Engender</em>, I immediately felt the energy of people coming together to tackle gender inequality in South African society. There was an understanding that the <em>Engender</em> series was being created to give a platform or a voice to people who could take us on a journey to show that our world is engendered, to help us understand how gender socialisation impacts on people and society, and to explore feminism as a  movement to organise and act against gender equality.</p>
<p>My role as researcher was to develop the content of each episode, that is to determine the focus of  each episode, to find guest panelists who have the knowledge, experience  and liveliness to discuss the topics in a way that could appeal to all types of viewers. This meant reading academic and popular material, interviewing individuals and the staff of organisations working on gender issues and feminism. It also meant finding video material and developing our own material that could show our viewers that gender inequality is not only a local, but a global challenge and how feminism was getting people to organise and take action.</p>
<p>Another exciting part of being on the team producing <em>Engender</em>, was going out onto the street to record interviews with different people about gender inequality and feminism. Speaking to people around the topics – <em>What is Feminism?</em>, <em>Representations of Gender in Media</em>, and <em>Intersectionality</em> – brought me to the realisation that many people had (and have) experiences of gender inequality and an awareness of feminism. Now, given an opportunity, they were willing to share and discuss. Explaining to people that <em>Engender</em> is a feminist programme was like lighting a fire. Many heated discussions followed starting with, “I thought men and women were equal, why do we still need feminism?” or “Yes we need feminism as gender inequality is so bad. We need more programmes like this.”</p>
<div id="attachment_1229" style="width: 625px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/11/ECEngender01.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1229" class="wp-image-1229 size-full" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/11/ECEngender01.jpg" alt="Erna in Open Studio" width="615" height="488" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/11/ECEngender01.jpg 615w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/11/ECEngender01-300x238.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 615px) 100vw, 615px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1229" class="wp-caption-text">Erna during a TV interview about Engender</p></div>
<p>Doing the research and being part of the team producing the programme meant that I learnt a lot about the history and development of feminism through time and what it means today. To me it means the recognition of the humanity and equal gender rights of every man and woman, of any age and ability, race, class, culture and ethnicity. I got a chance to be educated about gender and sexual minorities: lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, intersex, queer and asexual (LGBTIQA) people, and the terms and language that we should use to communicate and collaborate to make the spaces we move in safer and inclusive. This presented a challenge – using the wrong terms and language could easily offend or make someone feel excluded and we worked hard to make the production an inclusive, fair and collective space where every person involved could feel free and safe to voice their experience and opinions.</p>
<p>What I liked most about working on <em>Engender</em> was the enthusiasm and positive energy from all involved towards creating a programme where black women and allies controlled, managed and created the content. I did not feel alone, I felt like there was a collective of people collaborating at all times towards the same aim. TV is a powerful medium of communication, information and education that can reinforce gender inequality in society, but it can also be the means of raising awareness and empowering people to act for gender equality.</p>
<p>Each episode of <em>Engender</em> is an hour long, it is a talk show with guests and a studio audience, interesting and entertaining video clips showing global and local voices on each topic. With the pilot series we have just begun the journey of <em>Engender</em> – exploring gender inequality and feminist action to create a more just and equal world for all.</p>
<p>The fire has been lit! And I know we all look forward to hearing from everyone involved and the viewers about the impact of the programme, as much as we look forward to producing more programmes!</p>
<p>More about <em><a href="./../../../engender/index.html">More about Engender</a></em>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../coming-together-to-challenge-patriarchy/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Engendering a better world</title>
		<link>./../../../engendering-a-better-world/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../engendering-a-better-world/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 07:44:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[21st Century World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Work]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=1221</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[ I didn’t know much about feminism before working on the production; all that I knew was that a feminist is someone who believes in equal rights for men and women.]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Working on <em>Engender</em> has been an educational experience. I didn’t know much about feminism before working on the production; all that I knew was that a feminist is someone who believes in equal rights for men and women.</p>
<p>Throughout the pre-production process of <em>Engender</em> my knowledge about feminism broadened. Reading articles, blog posts, listening to conversations and attending workshops with the funder of the talk show added to my knowledge on feminism. Through conversations the team also shared their experiences on the different forms of discrimination and sexism they faced on a daily basis and discussed ways to raise awareness about this and hopefully change it.</p>
<p>Working on <em>Engender</em> has made me more observant about everyday sexism and discrimination, which I didn’t pick up on before. I didn’t pick up on it before because it’s always been there, even though it did make me feel uncomfortable. For example, if you go walking on the street you know that men will catcall you. It’s awful, but it’s the norm, so it’s expected, which it shouldn’t be. Other examples are that most, if not all, clothing shops only have pink clothes for girls and blue clothes for boys, and adverts on TV only show women in traditional domestic roles. It would be great to see a TV ad where the male in the household is busy in the kitchen.</p>
<p>The pilot of <em>Engender</em> consisted of three shows, which each explored a different topic. They were: What is Feminism, Media and Representation, and Intersectionality. Intersectionality is a word used to explain the way your gender, age, culture, class, sexual preference, ability, upbringing, race and surroundings influence your choices and opportunities. They also influence how society views you and treats you, which results in an experience of either privilege or oppression for the individual.</p>
<p>My role on the production was co-ordinator, which is basically making sure everyone and everything is where it needs to be, when it needs to be there. What I enjoyed the most, however, was going out on the streets to record the vox pops (asking the general public questions on the street). It’s always interesting to hear people’s opinions … if you manage to convince them to speak on camera.</p>
<div id="attachment_1222" style="width: 625px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/11/MJEngender01.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1222" class="wp-image-1222 size-full" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/11/MJEngender01.jpg" alt="Megan in studio" width="615" height="488" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/11/MJEngender01.jpg 615w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/11/MJEngender01-300x238.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 615px) 100vw, 615px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1222" class="wp-caption-text">Megan checks up on the studio activities during set-up</p></div>
<p>Working on <em>Engender</em> has also increased my knowledge about transgender people and a-gender people (people who don’t identify with being either man or woman). I also didn’t know much about transgender people and only learnt more about the topic when Caitlyn Jenner was highly covered in mainstream media. I find her reality show extremely informative as she speaks about the different issues she faces daily. One episode was about how she wanted to undergo surgery to make her voice more feminine because it still made her feel like a man. <em>Engender</em> has made me interested in learning more about transgender and a-gender people. In the future I hope we get to cover both as an <em>Engender</em> episode topic.</p>
<p>Going forward, I really hope we get feedback from viewers after the shows air. I’m curious to find out people’s reactions and whether it’s made them more observant about the world around them like it has made me.</p>
<p>More about <em><a href="./../../../engender/index.html">More about Engender</a></em>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../engendering-a-better-world/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Engender</title>
		<link>./../../../engender/index.html</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 19:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[21st Century World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspires me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Work]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=1193</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Engender is a feminist magazine TV programme that encourages South Africans to be bold and create the society we read about in our Constitution.]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/09/EngenderLogoAFWebsite1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1215" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/09/EngenderLogoAFWebsite1.jpg" alt="Engender Broadcast Times" width="640" height="360" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/09/EngenderLogoAFWebsite1.jpg 640w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/09/EngenderLogoAFWebsite1-300x169.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></p>
<p><em>Engender</em> is a feminist magazine TV programme that encourages South Africans to be bold and create the society we read about in our Constitution. We explore and expose gender inequality in society with the aim of making ours a better world for everyone, including our daughters and sons.</p>
<p>Our three part pilot examines society and argues that Feminism is still needed in a country hailed for its progressive Constitution, and in a world where we can communicate instantly with friends in different time zones.Despite policy and technological advances, we struggle to advance into a lived experience where we are treated equally regardless of where we place ourselves on the gender continuum, where boys are not discouraged from pursuing ballet, or girls are allowed to be raucous, where men may express their vulnerabilities and women may be confident without being called <em>aggressive</em> or <em>feisty</em>.</p>
<p><a href="./../../../femi-what/index.html">EPISODE 1</a> explores the origins of feminism, unpacks what feminism is and what it is not, and how feminist action has changed society globally and locally in South Africa.</p>
<p><a href="./../../../ways-of-seeing/index.html">EPISODE 2</a> examines the way media represent people through a gendered lens that normalises stereotypes about people based on perceived genders and sexualities.</p>
<p><a href="./../../../index.html?p=1322">EPISODE 3</a> grapples with the complexity of intersectional feminism to show how race, class, sex, age, and ablism intersect or interlock to multiply the effects of prejudice on an individual.</p>
<p><em>Engender</em> was broadcast on Cape Town Community TV during the 16 Days of Activism in 2015.</p>
<p>We hope you enjoy the programme and that it inspires debate within your network.</p>
<p>Read the post, <em><a href="./../../../engendering-a-better-world/index.html">Engendering a better world</a></em>.</p>
<p>Read the post, <em><a href="./../../../coming-together-to-challenge-patriarchy/index.html">Coming together to challenge patriarchy</a></em>.</p>
<p>Why don&#8217;t you like us on <a href="https://www.facebook.com/engendersa">Facebook</a> and follow us on <a href="https://twitter.com/engenderSA">Twitter</a>.</p>
<p>The three part pilot is funded by the <a href="https://za.boell.org/">Heinrich Boell Foundation</a>.</p>
<p><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/09/HBS-logo-1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1217" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/09/HBS-logo-1.jpg" alt="HBS logo" width="541" height="266" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/09/HBS-logo-1.jpg 541w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/09/HBS-logo-1-300x148.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 541px) 100vw, 541px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>My First Film</title>
		<link>./../../../my-first-film/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../my-first-film/index.html#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 17:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=1180</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Transcribing was my first main task. It’s time consuming, but I enjoy it because I like to hear what people have to say.]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When it came to deciding what I wanted to be when I grew up, I always questioned whether it should be just one thing. I mean it’s quite a commitment to pick one career for the rest of your life. That’s why I’m happy I chose to work in TV because there are always many different tasks to complete.</p>
<p>The chance to make what people see on TV has always been a dream and that’s why I studied Journalism and Media Studies. I find telling stories a magical thing and I definitely wanted to tell other people’s stories.</p>
<p>I was able to add Journalist to my CV when I worked on a news programme that focused on positive stories in the community, told through the voices of the characters. I liked being able to do this because I didn’t see myself as a journalist reporting on all the negative events in the world.</p>
<p>On the documentary film, <em>Mr Table Tennis</em>, I get to continue to explore the storytelling process as the production assistant. I am thrilled that I am making what I enjoy watching.</p>
<div id="attachment_1183" style="width: 610px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/MyFirstFilm.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1183" class="size-full wp-image-1183" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/MyFirstFilm.jpg" alt="Megan transcribes" width="600" height="472" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/MyFirstFilm.jpg 600w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/04/MyFirstFilm-300x236.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1183" class="wp-caption-text">Megan transcribes</p></div>
<p>Transcribing was my first main task. It’s time consuming, but I enjoy it because I like to hear what people have to say. Luckily, on <em>Mr Table Tennis</em>, people had interesting things to say. The best feeling was getting to know characters through their interviews. They made me laugh, sad, angry, excited, proud, happy and, overall, inspired. It’s strange that even though I haven’t met them, I feel connected to each person whose interview I transcribed.</p>
<p>Completing this documentary continues to be a great adventure because I’m working with great people. Reading some of the paper edit made the story come together and I started to picture the documentary in my head. I CAN’T WAIT to see the final product and to see my name in the credits.</p>
<p>by Megan Jonkers</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../my-first-film/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Working on Mr Table Tennis</title>
		<link>./../../../working-on-mr-table-tennis/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../working-on-mr-table-tennis/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2015 10:55:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=1161</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[I am enjoying this process of cobbling together our first grown-up documentary film.  “first” and “grown-up” because I have worked on and produced a few ...]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1"><span class="s1">I am enjoying this process of cobbling together our first grown-up documentary film. </span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">“first” and “grown-up” because I have worked on and produced a few short documentary films on my own. Some of them only a close circle of friends may have seen. I could call them exclusive, but only as a joke. I wonder how much I could sell these exclusive films for …</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">The enjoyment comes partly from the fact that the team is really invested in the people and the story. Eileen, our editor, e.g. is upset at how the storyline has developed. Two nights in a row she brought it up and expressed her incredulity and displeasure. I am pleased that she cares enough to be displeased. While I have spent three years working on the story, the researcher, Erna, has spent two months on the story, and the transcribers, Megan and Prudence, have spent less time on the project, but have certainly been most intimate with the characters through the transcription process, and at the time of writing this Eileen had only spent one week getting to know the characters and the story to date. I hope that Eileen’s response to the story is an indication of how viewers may feel when they watch the film. Fingers crossed. Eyes crossed. Legs crossed. </span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">There are a few anecdotes about people’s emotional connection to the story, but the one that has made me chuckle recently (because I received his final invoice) is the one about our sound person, Craig. Each of his invoices is for the project titled, Mr Table Tennis, the Meyer of table tennis, not simply for Mr Table Tennis.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">The team is attached to the people in the story and I hope that we do the people and the story justice. And I hope that I do the team justice. I hope that the film reflects the effort and commitment of everyone who worked on the film (both before the film was commissioned and after) and of those who have supported me at home. I hope, I hope, I hope.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Hope is not enough, of course. I need to put in the hard work to realise the hope. Only time will tell if I did enough. If I haven’t done enough, hopefully (that word again), I would have learnt what more needs to be done for next time. </span></p>
<div id="attachment_1172" style="width: 610px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/03/MrTTProductionStill0215.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1172" class="size-full wp-image-1172" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/03/MrTTProductionStill0215.jpg" alt="First shoot day with Vaughan (camera) and Craig (sound)" width="600" height="450" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/03/MrTTProductionStill0215.jpg 600w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/03/MrTTProductionStill0215-300x225.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1172" class="wp-caption-text">First shoot day with Vaughan (camera) and Craig (sound)</p></div>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../working-on-mr-table-tennis/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>2014 SA Table Tennis Open</title>
		<link>./../../../2014-sa-table-tennis-open/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../2014-sa-table-tennis-open/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 07:01:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Work]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=1131</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Thulani and I headed inland to Bloemfontein to follow Shane Overmeyer's progress through the South African Table Tennis Open Tournament.]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thulani and I headed inland to Bloemfontein to follow Shane Overmeyer&#8217;s progress through the South African Table Tennis Open Tournament. Shane is from Cape Town and has been the SA Open champion seven times. His goal this year was to hold the title for the eighth time.</p>
<p>Below is an excerpt from the trip that I put together for Cape Town TV&#8217;s Sports Federation TV.</p>
<p><iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/103012387?title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0&amp;color=e2bc3f" width="640" height="358" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/103012387">2014 South African Table Tennis Open</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/tls">Tina-Louise Smith</a> on <a href="https://vimeo.com/">Vimeo</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2014-sa-table-tennis-open/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Travels in Bloemfontein</title>
		<link>./../../../travels-in-bloemfontein/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../travels-in-bloemfontein/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 07:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=1111</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Before I forget, we were up at 06h00 one morning when the temperature registered -7 degrees Celsius.]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The South African Table Tennis Open Championships took place in Bloemfontein from 7 &#8211; 12 July this year.</p>
<p>Thulani and I headed north into the unexpectedly bitter inland temperatures to follow Shane Overmeyer&#8217;s progress through the tournament. Shane is from Cape Town and has been the SA Open champion seven times. <a title="Excerpt from 2014 SA Open" href="./../../../2014-sa-table-tennis-open/%20/index.html">His goal this year was to hold the title for the eighth time</a>.</p>
<p>The image of the keys to my bedroom at the B&amp;B on the frozen pond, should send chills down the spine of any warm blooded Capetonian &#8211; Capetonians balk at temperatures of 10 degrees Celsius. Thulani and I were outdoors at 22h00 in 1 degree Celsius, waiting waiting waiting for our closing shot. Before I forget, we were up at 06h00 one morning when the temperature registered -7 degrees Celsius to capture the sun rising over Bloemfontein.</p>
<p><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2014/08/Animals.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1126" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2014/08/Animals.jpg" alt="Animals" width="644" height="291" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2014/08/Animals.jpg 644w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2014/08/Animals-300x135.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 644px) 100vw, 644px" /></a></p>
<p><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2014/08/Temperatures.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1127" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2014/08/Temperatures.jpg" alt="Temperatures" width="644" height="291" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2014/08/Temperatures.jpg 644w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2014/08/Temperatures-300x135.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 644px) 100vw, 644px" /></a></p>
<p>But then we also got the chance to see zebras and giraffes strolling past us &#8230; in the middle of Bloemfontein. We went to Naval Hill to capture the sunrise, drove through the booms free of charge &#8211; all the security guard wanted to know, was whether we were coming to pray.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../travels-in-bloemfontein/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
