<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>LEAP School of Science and Maths &#8211; Accidental Films and TV</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>Documentary Film and TV Productions</description>
	<lastBuildDate>
	Tue, 31 Oct 2017 15:56:54 +0000	</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.1.6</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Meeting David Goldblatt</title>
		<link>./../../../meetingdavidgoldblatt/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../meetingdavidgoldblatt/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2010 20:23:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Inspires me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Goldblatt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LEAP School of Science and Maths]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Realistic]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=175</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[When I was working on Masupatsela Series I through Free Range Films, one of my favourite stories was the one I did with David Goldblatt. ...]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I was working on Masupatsela Series I through Free Range Films, one of my favourite stories was <a title="To blog at Free Range Films" href="http://www.freerangefilms.co.za/new-posts/coverstory/" target="_blank">the one I did with David Goldblatt</a>. Not only because I love looking at his photographs, but also partly because David Goldblatt was someone I had heard about before working on the series; and partly because of the unexpected way his photography connected with HIV and AIDS amongst the home based care, AIDS clinics and other HIV and AIDS support structures we featured around South Africa. We wanted to show unique ways that people were confronting the challenge of living with HIV and AIDS, and his way was truly unique in my mind.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/19426737?title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0&amp;color=7e2525" width="600" height="480" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>In Masupatsela Series II my top two projects were <a title="Opens Realistic web site in a new tab" href="http://realisticcbo.org/" target="_blank">Realistic</a> in Gugulethu and <a title="Opens LEAP web site in a new tab" href="http://www.leapschool.org.za/" target="_blank">LEAP Science and Maths School</a> in Pinelands. Both organisations are doing work that inspires and moves me. What this means for me is that if I can be involved in these projects in any way, I will be.</p>
<p>Last week, therefore, I was at Realistic to meet with Ncamile Solomon Madikane, the founder and director of Realistic to discuss a project we could collaborate on. I walked through the doors and found <a title="David Goldblatt at The Goodman Gallery" href="http://www.goodman-gallery.com/artists/davidgoldblatt" target="_blank">David Goldblatt</a> sitting in the waiting area. He explained to me the project he was working on. As I had been the first time when listening to him explain his motivation for that project back in 2007, I was struck once again by this man. There he was, about forty years older than me and still caring enough about the world and the people in it to follow his inspiration and keep on keeping on. At eighty years old he continues to try to make sense of the world &#8211; one man, his lenses and his camper.</p>
<p>I want to be like David Goldblatt when I&#8217;m big!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../meetingdavidgoldblatt/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
