<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>21st Century World &#8211; Accidental Films and TV</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>Documentary Film and TV Productions</description>
	<lastBuildDate>
	Tue, 31 Oct 2017 15:56:54 +0000	</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.1.6</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Feminism Across the Globe</title>
		<link>./../../../feminism-across-the-globe/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../feminism-across-the-globe/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 09:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[21st Century World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspires me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Work]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=1357</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Around mid-February we were contacted by Hisham Ashour who is studying Communication at Northwestern University in Qatar.]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-1360 size-full" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2017/02/HishamAshour.jpg" width="640" height="350" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2017/02/HishamAshour.jpg 640w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2017/02/HishamAshour-300x164.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Around mid-February 2017 we were contacted by Hisham Ashour who is studying Communication at Northwestern University in Qatar. Hisham and his group were interested to learn more about <em>Engender</em>, especially with regards to the intersection of race and feminism in South African media.</span></p>
<p>He is interested in the representation of feminism on TV because it is a topic which has recently become more and more relevant globally as media has made access to information around equality much easier than before. Another reason for his interest in <em>Engender</em> was that he was looking at media which was neither mainstream American nor mainstream European. (<em>Engender</em> was broadcast on the community TV platforms Cape Town TV and 1KZN TV in South Africa) The broad goal of his research was to complete a textual analysis along with the research to see how the themes of race and gender were conveyed. This will be part of his group&#8217;s presentation for their class called Understanding Media Contexts.</p>
<p>Hisham says they were interested in feminism because they believe it is often misunderstood. They also aimed to compare and contrast the different issues feminists face abroad and their media approaches.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../feminism-across-the-globe/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Femi-What??!</title>
		<link>./../../../femi-what/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../femi-what/index.html#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 12:49:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[21st Century World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Work]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=1306</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[PRESENTERS Ayanda Nabe &#124; Helga Jansen-Daugbjerg PANELISTS Gertrude Fester &#124; Dela Gwala &#124; Joy Watson RESEARCHER &#124; SCRIPTWRITER Erna Curry PRODUCER &#124; DIRECTOR Tina-Louise Smith]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/182676101?color=e2bc3f&amp;title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>PRESENTERS<br />
Ayanda Nabe | Helga Jansen-Daugbjerg</p>
<p>PANELISTS<br />
Gertrude Fester | Dela Gwala | Joy Watson</p>
<p>RESEARCHER | SCRIPTWRITER<br />
Erna Curry</p>
<p>PRODUCER | DIRECTOR<br />
Tina-Louise Smith</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../femi-what/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Show Me The Money</title>
		<link>./../../../show-me-the-money/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../show-me-the-money/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 19:42:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[21st Century World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Work]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=1282</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8220;As an historically disadvantaged filmmaker who has struggled to produce her films for the past 18 years, it is clear to me that black filmmakers ...]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2016/07/BFFContentPage.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1283" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2016/07/BFFContentPage.jpg" alt="BFFContentPage" width="640" height="350" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2016/07/BFFContentPage.jpg 640w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2016/07/BFFContentPage-300x164.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></p>
<p>&#8220;As an historically disadvantaged filmmaker who has struggled to produce her films for the past 18 years, it is clear to me that black filmmakers need economic support to be able to consistently produce films that contribute to a more honest and more representative national story. Through informal discussions I am aware that there are many more black filmmakers who know the same.</p>
<p>The South African film sector perpetuates the current status quo through established structures, ways of operating and systemic racism that continues to support white filmmakers over their historically disadvantaged counterparts. As much as government may be committed to economic redress and to creating opportunities for black filmmakers, its attempts are encumbered by structural racism and the economic reality bequeathed to South Africa by apartheid.</p>
<p>Black filmmakers in the Western Cape in particular are frustrated that their needs are not being understood, addressed and acknowledged. It is clear that government funding through the NFVF is also limited and other than the NFVF and the DTI, where do filmmakers go to fund their films?</p>
<p>This situation has remained unchanged in the Western Cape and it is a problem that has continued to bother me. I realize that we need funding beyond government for black and historically disadvantaged filmmakers in the Western Cape in particular and in South Africa in general. Because of this, I agreed to develop, co-ordinate and moderate this panel discussion at the Encounters South African International Documentary Festival this year.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2016/07/ShowMeTheMoneyReportFINALAFWebsite.pdf">Read the full report</a></p>
<p>Photographs at the panel discussion were taken by Shaun Swingler.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.encounters.co.za/"><img class="alignnone wp-image-1292 size-medium" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2016/07/ENCOUNTERS-LOGO-dark-red-page-001-300x300.jpg" alt="Encounters Logo" width="300" height="300" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2016/07/ENCOUNTERS-LOGO-dark-red-page-001-300x300.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2016/07/ENCOUNTERS-LOGO-dark-red-page-001-150x150.jpg 150w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2016/07/ENCOUNTERS-LOGO-dark-red-page-001-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2016/07/ENCOUNTERS-LOGO-dark-red-page-001-60x60.jpg 60w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2016/07/ENCOUNTERS-LOGO-dark-red-page-001.jpg 1181w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p><em>Show Me The Money</em> was hosted and supported by the Encounters South African International Documentary Festival</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../show-me-the-money/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Coming together to challenge patriarchy</title>
		<link>./../../../coming-together-to-challenge-patriarchy/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../coming-together-to-challenge-patriarchy/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 09:11:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[21st Century World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Work]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=1227</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[When I started working doing the research for the three pilot episodes of Engender, I immediately felt the energy of people coming together to tackle ...]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I started working doing the research for the three pilot episodes of <em>Engender</em>, I immediately felt the energy of people coming together to tackle gender inequality in South African society. There was an understanding that the <em>Engender</em> series was being created to give a platform or a voice to people who could take us on a journey to show that our world is engendered, to help us understand how gender socialisation impacts on people and society, and to explore feminism as a  movement to organise and act against gender equality.</p>
<p>My role as researcher was to develop the content of each episode, that is to determine the focus of  each episode, to find guest panelists who have the knowledge, experience  and liveliness to discuss the topics in a way that could appeal to all types of viewers. This meant reading academic and popular material, interviewing individuals and the staff of organisations working on gender issues and feminism. It also meant finding video material and developing our own material that could show our viewers that gender inequality is not only a local, but a global challenge and how feminism was getting people to organise and take action.</p>
<p>Another exciting part of being on the team producing <em>Engender</em>, was going out onto the street to record interviews with different people about gender inequality and feminism. Speaking to people around the topics – <em>What is Feminism?</em>, <em>Representations of Gender in Media</em>, and <em>Intersectionality</em> – brought me to the realisation that many people had (and have) experiences of gender inequality and an awareness of feminism. Now, given an opportunity, they were willing to share and discuss. Explaining to people that <em>Engender</em> is a feminist programme was like lighting a fire. Many heated discussions followed starting with, “I thought men and women were equal, why do we still need feminism?” or “Yes we need feminism as gender inequality is so bad. We need more programmes like this.”</p>
<div id="attachment_1229" style="width: 625px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/11/ECEngender01.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1229" class="wp-image-1229 size-full" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/11/ECEngender01.jpg" alt="Erna in Open Studio" width="615" height="488" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/11/ECEngender01.jpg 615w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/11/ECEngender01-300x238.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 615px) 100vw, 615px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1229" class="wp-caption-text">Erna during a TV interview about Engender</p></div>
<p>Doing the research and being part of the team producing the programme meant that I learnt a lot about the history and development of feminism through time and what it means today. To me it means the recognition of the humanity and equal gender rights of every man and woman, of any age and ability, race, class, culture and ethnicity. I got a chance to be educated about gender and sexual minorities: lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, intersex, queer and asexual (LGBTIQA) people, and the terms and language that we should use to communicate and collaborate to make the spaces we move in safer and inclusive. This presented a challenge – using the wrong terms and language could easily offend or make someone feel excluded and we worked hard to make the production an inclusive, fair and collective space where every person involved could feel free and safe to voice their experience and opinions.</p>
<p>What I liked most about working on <em>Engender</em> was the enthusiasm and positive energy from all involved towards creating a programme where black women and allies controlled, managed and created the content. I did not feel alone, I felt like there was a collective of people collaborating at all times towards the same aim. TV is a powerful medium of communication, information and education that can reinforce gender inequality in society, but it can also be the means of raising awareness and empowering people to act for gender equality.</p>
<p>Each episode of <em>Engender</em> is an hour long, it is a talk show with guests and a studio audience, interesting and entertaining video clips showing global and local voices on each topic. With the pilot series we have just begun the journey of <em>Engender</em> – exploring gender inequality and feminist action to create a more just and equal world for all.</p>
<p>The fire has been lit! And I know we all look forward to hearing from everyone involved and the viewers about the impact of the programme, as much as we look forward to producing more programmes!</p>
<p>More about <em><a href="./../../../engender/index.html">More about Engender</a></em>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../coming-together-to-challenge-patriarchy/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Engendering a better world</title>
		<link>./../../../engendering-a-better-world/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../engendering-a-better-world/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 07:44:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[21st Century World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Work]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=1221</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[ I didn’t know much about feminism before working on the production; all that I knew was that a feminist is someone who believes in equal rights for men and women.]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Working on <em>Engender</em> has been an educational experience. I didn’t know much about feminism before working on the production; all that I knew was that a feminist is someone who believes in equal rights for men and women.</p>
<p>Throughout the pre-production process of <em>Engender</em> my knowledge about feminism broadened. Reading articles, blog posts, listening to conversations and attending workshops with the funder of the talk show added to my knowledge on feminism. Through conversations the team also shared their experiences on the different forms of discrimination and sexism they faced on a daily basis and discussed ways to raise awareness about this and hopefully change it.</p>
<p>Working on <em>Engender</em> has made me more observant about everyday sexism and discrimination, which I didn’t pick up on before. I didn’t pick up on it before because it’s always been there, even though it did make me feel uncomfortable. For example, if you go walking on the street you know that men will catcall you. It’s awful, but it’s the norm, so it’s expected, which it shouldn’t be. Other examples are that most, if not all, clothing shops only have pink clothes for girls and blue clothes for boys, and adverts on TV only show women in traditional domestic roles. It would be great to see a TV ad where the male in the household is busy in the kitchen.</p>
<p>The pilot of <em>Engender</em> consisted of three shows, which each explored a different topic. They were: What is Feminism, Media and Representation, and Intersectionality. Intersectionality is a word used to explain the way your gender, age, culture, class, sexual preference, ability, upbringing, race and surroundings influence your choices and opportunities. They also influence how society views you and treats you, which results in an experience of either privilege or oppression for the individual.</p>
<p>My role on the production was co-ordinator, which is basically making sure everyone and everything is where it needs to be, when it needs to be there. What I enjoyed the most, however, was going out on the streets to record the vox pops (asking the general public questions on the street). It’s always interesting to hear people’s opinions … if you manage to convince them to speak on camera.</p>
<div id="attachment_1222" style="width: 625px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/11/MJEngender01.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1222" class="wp-image-1222 size-full" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/11/MJEngender01.jpg" alt="Megan in studio" width="615" height="488" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/11/MJEngender01.jpg 615w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/11/MJEngender01-300x238.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 615px) 100vw, 615px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1222" class="wp-caption-text">Megan checks up on the studio activities during set-up</p></div>
<p>Working on <em>Engender</em> has also increased my knowledge about transgender people and a-gender people (people who don’t identify with being either man or woman). I also didn’t know much about transgender people and only learnt more about the topic when Caitlyn Jenner was highly covered in mainstream media. I find her reality show extremely informative as she speaks about the different issues she faces daily. One episode was about how she wanted to undergo surgery to make her voice more feminine because it still made her feel like a man. <em>Engender</em> has made me interested in learning more about transgender and a-gender people. In the future I hope we get to cover both as an <em>Engender</em> episode topic.</p>
<p>Going forward, I really hope we get feedback from viewers after the shows air. I’m curious to find out people’s reactions and whether it’s made them more observant about the world around them like it has made me.</p>
<p>More about <em><a href="./../../../engender/index.html">More about Engender</a></em>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../engendering-a-better-world/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Engender</title>
		<link>./../../../engender/index.html</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 19:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[21st Century World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspires me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Work]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=1193</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Engender is a feminist magazine TV programme that encourages South Africans to be bold and create the society we read about in our Constitution.]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/09/EngenderLogoAFWebsite1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1215" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/09/EngenderLogoAFWebsite1.jpg" alt="Engender Broadcast Times" width="640" height="360" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/09/EngenderLogoAFWebsite1.jpg 640w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/09/EngenderLogoAFWebsite1-300x169.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></p>
<p><em>Engender</em> is a feminist magazine TV programme that encourages South Africans to be bold and create the society we read about in our Constitution. We explore and expose gender inequality in society with the aim of making ours a better world for everyone, including our daughters and sons.</p>
<p>Our three part pilot examines society and argues that Feminism is still needed in a country hailed for its progressive Constitution, and in a world where we can communicate instantly with friends in different time zones.Despite policy and technological advances, we struggle to advance into a lived experience where we are treated equally regardless of where we place ourselves on the gender continuum, where boys are not discouraged from pursuing ballet, or girls are allowed to be raucous, where men may express their vulnerabilities and women may be confident without being called <em>aggressive</em> or <em>feisty</em>.</p>
<p><a href="./../../../femi-what/index.html">EPISODE 1</a> explores the origins of feminism, unpacks what feminism is and what it is not, and how feminist action has changed society globally and locally in South Africa.</p>
<p><a href="./../../../ways-of-seeing/index.html">EPISODE 2</a> examines the way media represent people through a gendered lens that normalises stereotypes about people based on perceived genders and sexualities.</p>
<p><a href="./../../../index.html?p=1322">EPISODE 3</a> grapples with the complexity of intersectional feminism to show how race, class, sex, age, and ablism intersect or interlock to multiply the effects of prejudice on an individual.</p>
<p><em>Engender</em> was broadcast on Cape Town Community TV during the 16 Days of Activism in 2015.</p>
<p>We hope you enjoy the programme and that it inspires debate within your network.</p>
<p>Read the post, <em><a href="./../../../engendering-a-better-world/index.html">Engendering a better world</a></em>.</p>
<p>Read the post, <em><a href="./../../../coming-together-to-challenge-patriarchy/index.html">Coming together to challenge patriarchy</a></em>.</p>
<p>Why don&#8217;t you like us on <a href="https://www.facebook.com/engendersa">Facebook</a> and follow us on <a href="https://twitter.com/engenderSA">Twitter</a>.</p>
<p>The three part pilot is funded by the <a href="https://za.boell.org/">Heinrich Boell Foundation</a>.</p>
<p><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/09/HBS-logo-1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1217" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/09/HBS-logo-1.jpg" alt="HBS logo" width="541" height="266" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/09/HBS-logo-1.jpg 541w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2015/09/HBS-logo-1-300x148.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 541px) 100vw, 541px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mandela Tributes at a Community TV Station</title>
		<link>./../../../mandela-tributes-at-a-community-tv-station/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../mandela-tributes-at-a-community-tv-station/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 19:57:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[21st Century World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Work]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=1079</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[15 December 2013. Nelson Mandela is dead and now also buried. I work at Cape Town TV, a community TV station in Cape Town and ...]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>15 December 2013. Nelson Mandela is dead and now also buried.</p>
<p>I work at <a title="Cape Town TV" href="http://www.capetowntv.org/">Cape Town TV</a>, a community TV station in Cape Town and that Friday morning a decision had been made to postpone our five day fundraising Telethon to pay tribute to Nelson Mandela. From Friday 6 December to Monday 9 December, we broadcast live tributes in one to two hour slots. This was a major accomplishment for an under resourced, under funded television station, but with the support of our community members and many headless chicken moments we pulled it off at short notice.</p>
<p>The idea was to provide a platform for our community members to pay tribute to President Mandela. You could come in to recite a poem, perform a piece of music, or simply say a few words.  As a community TV station I believe this platform we provided was the essence of what it means to be a community TV station.</p>
<p>All sorts of people came through, the famous (and, to some, the infamous), religious leaders, chiefs and ordinary members of the public. The better known included Mary Burton, Marius Fransman, and Dan Plato. On the Friday we scrambled to get guests into the studio, but people wanted to come and so, they came. On the Saturday we seemed to have too many people coming through and we were concerned about being able to give all the people airtime. We had to cut short the amount of time allocated each person or group. At one stage, when I returned from the studio where the tributes were being done to the main office where my desk is, I was stunned by the amount of people crowding the space. For a brief moment my flight instinct kicked in as my first thought was <em>How will we accommodate all these people?</em> I quickly regained composure and then felt overwhelmed that our community had responded so positively to our platform for tributes. It affirmed that we were doing something that spoke directly to a need of our community members.</p>
<p><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2013/12/SaturdaySundayInterviews.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1100" alt="SaturdaySundayInterviews" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2013/12/SaturdaySundayInterviews.jpg" width="644" height="271" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2013/12/SaturdaySundayInterviews.jpg 644w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2013/12/SaturdaySundayInterviews-300x126.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 644px) 100vw, 644px" /></a></p>
<p>On Saturday we went live from 19h00 &#8211; 21h00. The first people were there by three o&#8217; clock &#8211; a mother and her son, who came to sing and play the accordion. They sat in our lounge for four hours waiting for their chance to perform their tribute.</p>
<p>By the Sunday we were old hands at the tributes. Although we did not have all the tributes confirmed at the start of the day, by the end of the broadcast all our minutes had been substantially filled and there was no extra time for the Reverend who had paid tribute and then wanted to close the broadcast with a prayer.</p>
<p>Before any of my colleagues read this and think I forgot about Monday&#8217;s broadcast, or that I do not count it as one of the tribute broadcasts, this is not the case. Monday&#8217;s live broadcast aired from 16h00 – 17h00 which is the slot of our flagship youth programme, <em>EkSê</em> (I Say). While the preceding live tributes were staffed by mostly full time staff, <em>EkSê</em> was crewed by our volunteers, who are mainly young people, who come to the station to gain TV experience. They did a sterling job and I take my hat off to the presenter, Millz, who was the only presenter on the programme and maintained a cool, calm presence throughout his first ever live TV show!</p>
<p><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2013/12/EkSeTribute.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1101" alt="EkSeTribute" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2013/12/EkSeTribute.jpg" width="644" height="353" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2013/12/EkSeTribute.jpg 644w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2013/12/EkSeTribute-300x164.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 644px) 100vw, 644px" /></a></p>
<p>I wanted to write about this as an instance of community TV doing what community TV is meant to do, which is to provide access to broadcast facilities for community members and the platform for community members to express themselves. It is a simple goal that I think we were able to realise in the way that community members were able to use the station to pay tribute to Nelson Mandela.</p>
<p>The thoughts expressed in this blog are entirely my own and in no way reflect the official position of Cape Town TV.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../mandela-tributes-at-a-community-tv-station/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mr Table Tennis</title>
		<link>./../../../mr-table-tennis/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../mr-table-tennis/index.html#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 22:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[21st Century World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Work]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=1047</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Mr Table Tennis is the inter-generational story of Pedro and Cody Meyer. Their big dreams unfold against an ambiguous socio-economic climate that determines the choices ...]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/61664145?title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0&amp;color=e2bc3f" width="640" height="358" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p><em>Mr Table Tennis</em> is the inter-generational story of Pedro and Cody Meyer. Their big dreams unfold against an ambiguous socio-economic climate that determines the choices they make in life and in table tennis.</p>
<p>Pedro Meyer was a brilliant table tennis player and a showman. Living under apartheid meant he was unable to test his game on the international stage. Today he has placed his dreams of world domination in his grandson, Cody.</p>
<p>Growing up in the New South Africa, Cody has been able to travel and compete internationally and he knows his family would like him to continue where his grandfather left off.</p>
<p>Cody is torn between pursuing his new passion, DJing, and table tennis, which is in his blood.</p>
<p><a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2013/03/MrTableTennisWebsiteBronzeLaurels.jpg"><img class="wp-image-1259 alignnone" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2013/03/MrTableTennisWebsiteBronzeLaurels.jpg" alt="MrTableTennisWebsiteBronzeLaurels" width="600" height="338" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2013/03/MrTableTennisWebsiteBronzeLaurels.jpg 800w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2013/03/MrTableTennisWebsiteBronzeLaurels-300x169.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></a></p>
<h3>COMMENTS</h3>
<blockquote>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Loved it! Beautifully nuanced, and soulful. Great generational juxtaposition. Who woulda thought table tennis played such a pivotal role in the struggle as the first sporting code to force sanctions. </span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Talk about untold stories!   </span>DINGI NTULI, PRODUCER, MASALA FILMWORKS</p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Congratulations on the success of your documentary, Mr Table Tennis. Mum and I watched it together and were intrigued and chuffed with the documentary. It is great that you bring such important history to life for our communities and country.    LESLEY ANN FOSTER, EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR, MASIMANYANE WOMEN&#8217;S SUPPORT CENTRE</span></p>
</blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../mr-table-tennis/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>African Queen</title>
		<link>./../../../african-queen/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../african-queen/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 13:58:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[20th Century Left Behind]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[21st Century World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=1021</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[African Queen was the last film I made in the series and seems to always be the first film that is selected for festivals and screenings. ]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/37123035?color=7e2525" frameborder="0" width="640" height="358"></iframe></p>
<p><em>African Queen</em> was the last film I made in the series and seems to always be the first film that is selected for festivals and screenings. I enjoyed making the film and working with the people in the story. Lorraine, Ellen and everyone else in the film were all extremely accommodating and patient with the process and I think this is reflected in a certain lightness I feel about the film.</p>
<p>I can&#8217;t put my finger on it yet, but this film feels like poetry. Maybe this comes from the wind, maybe it comes from the shadows, maybe it comes from the natural resources and ingenuity that go into the products &#8211; I couldn&#8217;t say. It&#8217;s just a feeling.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.bigfish.org.za/"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-980" title="BFLogo" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2012/05/BFLogo1-150x150.png" alt="" width="150" height="150" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2012/05/BFLogo1-150x150.png 150w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2012/05/BFLogo1-60x60.png 60w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /></a>   <a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2012/05/LittlePondLogo.png"><img class="alignnone size-thumbnail wp-image-978" title="LittlePondLogo" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2012/05/LittlePondLogo-150x150.png" alt="" width="150" height="150" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2012/05/LittlePondLogo-150x150.png 150w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2012/05/LittlePondLogo-60x60.png 60w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /></a>   <a href="http://www.nlb.org.za/"><img class="alignnone size-thumbnail wp-image-974" title="NationalLottery" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2012/05/NationalLottery-150x150.png" alt="" width="150" height="150" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2012/05/NationalLottery-150x150.png 150w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2012/05/NationalLottery-60x60.png 60w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../african-queen/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cape Town Is Not For Me</title>
		<link>./../../../cape-town-is-not-for-me/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../cape-town-is-not-for-me/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 13:20:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Accidental Films]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[21st Century World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=1007</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Of the four UpCycling films I directed this is my favourite.]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/37119108?color=7e2525" frameborder="0" width="640" height="360"></iframe></p>
<p>Of the four UpCycling films I directed this is my favourite. I think I was able to weave together a few stories in a way that successfully showed the impact of the weaving project on families&#8217; lives. The number of voices in this film also create a more interesting film and one that feels closer to a documentary than a promotional film for me.</p>
<p>Despite this being my favourite, it has not yet been selected for festivals and I am waiting out the days (which have been rather long at the time of posting this) when I achieve enough distance, to be able to see its shortcomings. Unless of course, you want to mention them in the comments below.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.bigfish.org.za/"><img class="alignnone size-thumbnail wp-image-980" title="BFLogo" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2012/05/BFLogo1-150x150.png" alt="" width="150" height="150" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2012/05/BFLogo1-150x150.png 150w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2012/05/BFLogo1-60x60.png 60w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /></a>   <a href="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2012/05/LittlePondLogo.png"><img class="alignnone size-thumbnail wp-image-978" title="LittlePondLogo" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2012/05/LittlePondLogo-150x150.png" alt="" width="150" height="150" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2012/05/LittlePondLogo-150x150.png 150w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2012/05/LittlePondLogo-60x60.png 60w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /></a>   <a href="http://www.nlb.org.za/"><img class="alignnone size-thumbnail wp-image-974" title="NationalLottery" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2012/05/NationalLottery-150x150.png" alt="" width="150" height="150" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2012/05/NationalLottery-150x150.png 150w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2012/05/NationalLottery-60x60.png 60w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../cape-town-is-not-for-me/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
